{"text": ["Most", "offerings", "to", "Hathor", "were", "used", "for", "their", "symbolism", ",", "not", "for", "their", "intrinsic", "value", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "foundation", "was", "laid", "by", "General", "Muhammad", "Ayub", "Khan", "on", "21", "March", "1950", "and", "opening", "ceremony", "was", "headed", "by", "Governor", "of", "Punjab", "Sardar", "Abdur", "Rab", "Nishtar", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "prototype", "was", "based", "on", "a", "Bell", "205", "airframe", "equipped", "with", "a", "Lycoming", "T53-L-702", "engine", "of", "1,900", "shp", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "museum", "includes", "a", "re-created", "Korean", "traditional", "garden", ",", "known", "as", "the", "``", "Hee", "Won", "Garden", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "club", "was", "known", "as", "the", "New", "York", "Raiders", "in", "the", "previous", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "screenplay", "was", "written", "by", "Jolene", "Rice", "and", "it", "was", "directed", "by", "Mario", "Azzopardi", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "recorded", "more", "than", "EUR", "2", "billion", "in", "net", "sales", ",", "with", "orders", "4", "percent", "higher", "than", "in", "the", "preceding", "year", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Not", "yet", "realizing", "the", "scale", "of", "what", "occurred", ",", "the", "sisters", "applied", "to", "different", "institutions", ",", "proposing", "the", "creation", "of", "a", "body", "called", "the", "Union", "of", "monasticism", "'s", "adherents", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Jane", "Live", "``", "was", "released", "on", "March", "3", ",", "2017", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "was", "the", "first", "presidential", "election", "in", "which", "Hawaii", "participated", ";", "the", "state", "had", "been", "admitted", "to", "the", "Union", "just", "over", "a", "year", "earlier", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Along", "with", "other", "misfortunes", "in", "the", "1920s", ",", "foot-and-mouth", "disease", "struck", "in", "1926", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "story", "'s", "details", "were", "featured", "on", "Doctor", "Who", "Magazine", "issue", "255", ",", "in", "August", "1997", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "highway", "crosses", "US", "78", "again", ",", "this", "time", ",", "signed", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "was", "part", "of", "a", "series", "of", "events", "known", "as", "the", "Colorado", "War", "and", "was", "preceded", "by", "the", "Hungate", "massacre", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Moffett", "Federal", "Airfield", "has", "occasional", "air", "traffic", ",", "with", "an", "average", "of", "5-10", "flights", "landing", "per", "day", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Waffle", "House", "has", "an", "extensive", "disaster", "management", "plan", "with", "on-site", "and", "portable", "generators", "and", "positioned", "food", "and", "ice", "ahead", "of", "severe", "weather", "events", "such", "as", "a", "hurricane", "."], "label": ["B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["From", "1736", "to", "1745", "it", "was", "also", "the", "seat", "of", "the", "Kingdom", "of", "Slavonia", "administration", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "lexis", ",", "grammar", "and", "phonology", "are", "also", "likely", "to", "influence", "the", "usage", "of", "spoken", "French", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O"]}
{"text": ["End", "of", "support", "for", "the", "``", "Free", "Use", "''", "version", "of", "BitKeeper", "was", "officially", "July", "1", ",", "2005", ",", "and", "users", "were", "required", "to", "switch", "to", "the", "commercial", "version", "or", "change", "version", "control", "system", "by", "then", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "prize", "gone", "on", "to", "become", "one", "of", "the", "richest", "and", "most", "prestigious", "poetry", "competitions", "in", "the", "country", ",", "and", "is", "now", "known", "as", "the", "Newcastle", "Poetry", "Prize", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "committed", "to", "the", "University", "of", "Miami", "to", "play", "college", "football", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["13.", ",", "The", "Glasgow", "Herald", ",", "1", "June", "1910", ",", "pg", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "I-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "city", "also", "has", "an", "Itagüí", "Coliseum", "where", "soccer", "practice", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "led", "to", "the", "demolishing", "of", "Lantern", "House", ",", "and", "building", "40", "low-rise", "flats", "in", "their", "place", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Considering", "the", "issues", "involved", "with", "biodiversity", "and", "the", "broader", "issues", "in", "TRIPs", "(", "involving", "all", "forms", "of", "cultural", "expressions", ",", "not", "just", "those", "associated", "with", "biodiversity", "–", "including", "traditional", "designs", ",", "music", ",", "songs", ",", "stories", ",", "etc", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "was", "followed", "in", "September", "2007", "by", "the", "Sadrist", "Movement", ",", "who", "complained", "the", "Alliance", "was", "``", "dominated", "by", "some", "parties", "''", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "star", "is", "radiating", "1,592", "times", "the", "Sun", "'s", "luminosity", "from", "its", "enlarged", "photosphere", "at", "an", "effective", "temperature", "of", "5,300", "K.", "It", "is", "a", "source", "of", "X-ray", "emission", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", ",", "CatholicTV", "presents", "weekday", "and", "Saturday", "Masses", "from", "the", "chapel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
