{"text": ["HEMA", "forms", "deep", "resinous", "tags", "and", "then", "occludes", "the", "dentinal", "tubules", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Ito", "M", "o", "moka", ",", "one", "of", "the", "members", "commented", "that", "``", "I", "'m", "honored", "to", "be", "able", "to", "perform", "at", "Sanrio", "Puroland", "where", "I", "'ve", "been", "visited", "many", "times", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "parties", "also", "reaffirmed", "their", "obligations", "to", "comply", "fully", "with", "the", "Limited", "Test", "Ban", "Treaty", "of", "1963", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "film", "was", "directed", "and", "written", "by", "Byambasuren", "Davaa", "and", "Luigi", "Falorni", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "became", "part", "of", "the", "Fort", "George", "Island", "Cultural", "State", "Park", "in", "1989", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "network", "was", "set", "up", "in", "1988", "as", "a", "response", "to", "the", "Chernobyl", "disaster", "in", "1986", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1956", "he", "was", "appointed", "at", "the", "British", "Diplomatic", "Service", "and", "served", "in", "the", "Foreign", "Office", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bombay", "High", "Court", "directs", "TV", "Today", "Network", "to", "Pay", "5", "lakh", "fine", "imposed", "by", "BARC"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Many", "were", "driven", "away", "from", "Christianity", "by", "that", "faith", "'s", ",", "as", "they", "saw", "it", ",", "overly", "strict", "application", "of", "doctrine", "and", "its", "denial", "of", "certain", "phenomena", "such", "as", "astral", "projection", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Also", ",", "it", "is", "adjacent", "to", "the", "hamlet", "of", "Woodbury", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Akshay", "Parija", "presently", "serves", "as", "Board", "Member", "and", "Executive", "Director", "to", "Blue", "Lines", "Shipping", "Group", "which", "he", "founded", "in", "the", "year", "2010", "."], "label": ["B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "summer", "of", "2019", ",", "the", "Sunset", "Walk", "restaurants", "and", "shops", "opened", "next", "to", "the", "Margaritaville", "Resort", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "selected", "to", "play", "in", "his", "first", "NBA", "All-Star", "Game", "in", "2013", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Her", "Ph.D.", "is", "in", "Chemistry", "from", "the", "University", "of", "Arizona", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["JASBUG", "is", "a", "security", "bug", "disclosed", "in", "February", "2015", "and", "affecting", "core", "components", "of", "the", "Microsoft", "Windows", "Operating", "System", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "interior", "of", "the", "fortress", "was", "demolished", "during", "the", "Koca", "rebellion", "in", "1788", ",", "and", "a", "caravanserai", ",", "which", "is", "built", "in", "the", "same", "way", "as", "the", "fortress", ",", "is", "found", "in", "its", "vicinity", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "November", "and", "December", "1965", ",", "the", "duo", "undertook", "just", "such", "an", "adventure", ",", "one", "that", "became", "the", "documentary", "film", "``", "Crossroads", "Alice", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "June", "1945", ",", "an", "order", "was", "placed", "for", "26", "DC-7", "aircraft", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bondi", "has", "justified", "those", "contacts", "and", "her", "speeches", "before", "leading", "Scientologists", "by", "arguing", "that", "the", "group", "wishes", "to", "help", "her", "crack", "down", "on", "human", "trafficking", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "made", "a", "cameo", "in", "``", "The", "LEGO", "Batman", "Movie", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "current", "boathouse", "is", "the", "third", "location", "the", "station", "has", "used", "on", "Hayling", "island", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "current", "team", "is", "Primera", "División", "de", "Chile", "side", "Universidad", "de", "Concepción", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["Currency", "strength", "is", "calculated", "from", "the", "U.S.", "Dollar", "Index", ",", "which", "is", "used", "as", "a", "reference", "for", "other", "currency", "indexes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "made", "Bengali", "-language", "films", "that", "were", "noted", "for", "introducing", "many", "film", "directors", "who", "later", "became", "famous", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "support", "of", "these", "operations", "in", "December", "the", "brigade", "moved", "into", "the", "Sinai", ";", "their", "first", "large", "battle", "came", "during", "the", "Battle", "of", "Magdhaba", "on", "23", "December", ",", "two", "days", "after", "the", "brigade", "was", "formed", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "guidance", "and", "control", "system", "for", "SA-7", "is", "shown", "in", "Figure", "7", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "group", ",", "along", "with", "the", "NGC", "7582", "group", "form", "the", "Grus", "cloud", ",", "a", "region", "of", "elevated", "galaxy", "density", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "was", "instrumental", "in", "beginning", "the", "Washington", "Post", "Children", "'s", "Book", "Guild", "Nonfiction", "Award", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "idea", "was", "to", "design", "and", "construct", "the", "Bengaluru", "Football", "Stadium", "like", "that", "but", "with", "a", "final", "capacity", "of", "90,000", "instead", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "rishi", "of", "10.47", "is", "called", "Saptagu", ",", "while", "that", "of", "10.48-50", "is", "likewise", "called", "Indra", "Vaikuntha", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O"]}
