{"text": ["Corning", "was", "let", "go", "from", "WFAA", "in", "April", "2019", ",", "without", "being", "granted", "an", "on-air", "goodbye", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "counterfeited", "notes", "were", "created", "at", "the", "Sachsenhausen", "concentration", "camp", "by", "prisoners", "who", "were", "experts", "in", "forgery", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "virtual", "representation", "of", "the", "McKenna", "MOUT", "site", "was", "based", "on", "the", "shooter", "PC", "game", ",", "Tom", "Clancy", "'s", "Rainbow", "Six", "3", ":", "Raven", "Shield1", ",", "which", "focused", "on", "small", "unit", "warfare", "in", "urban", "environments", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Colony", "of", "Rhode", "Island", "and", "Providence", "Plantations", "took", "no", "active", "role", "in", "provoking", "the", "conflict", ",", "but", "its", "geographical", "location", "caused", "it", "to", "suffer", "more", "than", "any", "other", "colony", "."], "label": ["O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lambrino", "developed", "into", "one", "of", "the", "most", "sought-after", "pianists", "of", "his", "time", "."], "label": ["B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "CNN3", "``", "is", "one", "of", "the", "three", "homologous", "calponin", "isoform", "genes", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Another", "variation", "of", "Surya", "Majapahit", "is", "the", "eight", "pointed", "sun", "rays", "with", "the", "god", "of", "sun", "Surya", "in", "the", "center", "riding", "celestial", "horse", "or", "chariot", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "anticipated", "limitations", "on", "determining", "weapons", "effects", "inspired", "efforts", "by", "the", "Special", "Weapons", "Center", "and", "Sandia", "Corporation", "to", "develop", "methods", "of", "simulating", "nuclear", "effects", "with", "non-nuclear", "techniques", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "the", "home", "of", "Peñarol", "La", "Mesilla", "football", "club", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2021", ",", "TD", "Garden", "will", "host", "the", "2021", "Laver", "Cup", "in", "September", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "RYA", "2012", "Portsmouth", "Yardstick", "(", "PY", ")", "Number", "for", "the", "Stratos", "is", "1092", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pauahi", "Crater", "is", "a", "volcanic", "crater", "measuring", "long", ",", "up", "to", "some", "across", ",", "and", "deep", "in", "Hawaii", "Volcanoes", "National", "Park", "at", "."], "label": ["B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "time", ",", "it", "was", "planned", "that", "the", "ESPN", "Zone", "restaurant", "would", "increase", "promotional", "efforts", "with", "the", "two", "sports", "teams", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Fourth", "Runner-Up", "or", "``", "Miss", "Top", "Model", "República", "Dominicana", "''", "will", "enter", "Top", "Model", "of", "the", "World", "2014", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "best", "known", "for", "winning", "the", "World", "Road", "Race", "Championships", ",", "in", "2008", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Some", "exclusions", "include", "a", "maximum", "loss", "limit", "of", "$", "50,000", "while", "others", "require", "a", "loan", "term", "of", "less", "than", "84", "months", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Some", "Austrians", "such", "as", "Karl", "Lueger", "also", "used", "pan-Germanism", "as", "a", "form", "of", "populism", "to", "further", "their", "own", "political", "goals", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Later", ",", "he", "resolved", "to", "be", "at", "the", "forefront", "of", "the", "Dogri", "literacy", "movement", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", "to", "its", "medical", ",", "nursing", ",", "and", "dental", "divisions", "(", "see", "below", ")", ",", "it", "merged", "with", "the", "Oregon", "Graduate", "Institute", "of", "Science", "and", "Technology", "in", "2001", ",", "taking", "on", "its", "current", "name", "and", "composition", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "a", "decade", "after", "the", "Islamic", "revolution", "of", "1979", "all", "ashik", "performances", "were", "banned", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Upon", "graduation", ",", "Nooshin", "began", "making", "short", "films", "and", "commercials", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Following", "the", "end", "of", "this", "tour", ",", "she", "auditioned", "to", "become", "a", "presenter", "on", "Channel", "4", "'s", "late-night", "magazine", "show", "``", "The", "Word", "``", ",", "beating", "more", "than", "five", "thousand", "hopefuls", "for", "the", "job", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "has", "been", "called", "an", "``", "iconic", "Cold", "War", "text", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "currencies", "of", "the", "three", "countries", "were", "interchangeable", "at", "par", "value", "under", "the", "Interchangeability", "Agreement", "until", "8", "May", "1973", "when", "the", "Malaysian", "government", "decided", "to", "terminate", "it", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
