{"text": ["These", "airlines", "connect", "more", "than", "80", "cities", "across", "India", ",", "and", "are", "joined", "by", "several", "foreign", "airlines", "in", "providing", "international", "routes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "college", "was", "officially", "chartered", "by", "the", "Los", "Angeles", "Board", "of", "Education", "in", "June", "1949", ",", "and", "was", "located", "on", "the", "campus", "of", "Van", "Nuys", "High", "School", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["Through", "the", "day", ",", "she", "continued", "to", "shell", "those", "islands", ",", "and", ",", "in", "late", "afternoon", ",", "added", "Bennett", "Island", "to", "her", "targets", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Stop", "The", "Presses", "``", "is", "a", "2008", "film", "which", "discussed", "how", "the", "Internet", "has", "changed", "the", "nature", "of", "print", "journalism", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sunward", "Aerospace", "also", "produces", "a", "line", "of", "wood", "kits", "which", "include", "a", "trebuchet", ",", "a", "catapult", ",", "a", "ballista", "and", "an", "elastic", "powered", "racer", "."], "label": ["B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Tapers", "played", "only", "28", "games", "during", "the", "abbreviated", "1962–1963", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "causes", "of", "acquired", "antithrombin", "deficiency", "are", "easier", "to", "find", "than", "the", "hereditary", "deficiency", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sparr", "was", "confirmed", "by", "the", "United", "States", "Senate", "on", "April", "5", ",", "1990", ",", "and", "received", "his", "commission", "on", "April", "6", ",", "1990", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "is", "in", "line", "with", "Chávez", "'s", "Socialism", "of", "the", "21st", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Various", "researchers", "have", "proposed", "that", "the", "atmosphere", "of", "Io", "freezes", "onto", "the", "surface", "when", "it", "passes", "into", "the", "shadow", "of", "Jupiter", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["So", "all", "power", "stations", "under", "CLP", "Power", "burn", "ULSD", "instead", "of", "higher", "sulfur", "alternatives", "now", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Most", "modern", "bobsled", "roller", "coasters", "are", "made", "of", "steel", ";", "however", ",", "the", "first", "bobsled", "coasters", ",", "known", "as", "``", "Flying", "Turns", "``", ",", "were", "made", "of", "wood", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "January–February", "1942", ",", "``", "Shikinami", "``", "was", "assigned", "to", "the", "escort", "of", "the", "aircraft", "carrier", "as", "it", "conducted", "air", "strikes", "in", "the", "Java", "Sea", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "project", "to", "convert", "the", "40,000", "Spanish", "coins", "took", "over", "a", "year", "to", "complete", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Nobel", "citation", "was", "``", "for", "pioneering", "contributions", "to", "the", "development", "of", "neutron", "scattering", "techniques", "for", "studies", "of", "condensed", "matter", "''", "and", "``", "for", "the", "development", "of", "neutron", "spectroscopy", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "farmstead", "is", "set", "on", "either", "side", "of", "Town", "Highway", "25", ",", "a", "spur", "road", "that", "acts", "as", "the", "farm", "driveway", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["These", "caused", "the", "work", "to", "be", "shelved", "after", "the", "outbreak", "of", "[", "[", "World", "War", "II", "]", "]", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "event", "was", "taken", "by", "both", "Protestants", "and", "Catholics", "as", "a", "sign", "of", "God", "'", "s", "displeasure", "at", "the", "other", "faction", "'s", "actions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Continental", "Celtic", "languages", "are", "attested", "almost", "exclusively", "through", "inscriptions", "and", "place-names", "."], "label": ["B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "ineffective", "and", "was", "repealed", "20", "years", "later", "by", "the", "Ecclesiastical", "Titles", "Act", "1871", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["the", "earthquake", "and", "tsunami", "caused", "the", "compound", "accident", "(", "hereinafter", "called", "Fukushima", "Daiichi", "Nuclear", "Accident", ")", "consisting", "of", "Station", "BlackOut", "(", "SBO", ")", "incident", ","], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Ritz", ",", "which", "has", "showering", "facilities", "and", "two", "saunas", ",", "also", "includes", "a", "stage", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "branch", ",", "which", "opened", "in", "May", "1929", ",", "was", "the", "sixth", "NPL", "branch", "to", "open", "between", "1923", "and", "1946", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "November", "1956", "it", "served", "as", "an", "initial", "place", "for", "housing", "for", "refugees", "from", "the", "1956", "Hungarian", "Revolution", "until", "June", "1957", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
