{"text": ["Moved", "to", "first", "weekend", "in", "January", "based", "on", "predicted", "New", "Hampshire", "primary", "date", "of", "Tuesday", ",", "January", "8", ",", "2008", ",", "which", "came", "to", "pass", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "the", "society", "also", "regularly", "performed", "in", "other", "rooms", "of", "the", "Association", "building", "(", "most", "notably", "for", "its", "annual", "festival", "of", "student-authored", "one-act", "plays", "called", "3SOME", ")", ",", "in", "outdoor", "theatre", "settings", "on", "campus", ",", "the", "University", "Theatre", "in", "the", "Christchurch", "Arts", "Centre", ",", "and", "in", "roving", "street", "theatre", "events", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Media", "coverage", "of", "the", "1991", "Dili", "Massacre", "helped", "revitalise", "international", "support", "for", "the", "East", "Timorese", "independence", "movement", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "the", "plug", "collapsed", ",", "the", "river", "still", "was", "forced", "to", "travel", "north", "through", "the", "range", "before", "finding", "a", "new", "outlet", "near", "present-day", "Paterson", "where", "it", "could", "manage", "the", "eastern", "turn", "toward", "the", "sea", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dramane", "Kone", "is", "the", "son", "of", "well-known", "musical", "griot/master", "drummer", "Dougoutigui", "Kone", "."], "label": ["B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O"]}
{"text": ["Christopher", "Lee", "was", "recruited", "into", "the", "Royal", "Navy", "'s", "Joint", "Intelligence", "Reserve", "Branch", "and", "in", "the", "1970s", "completed", "a", "study", "of", "the", "Order", "of", "Battle", "of", "the", "Soviet", "Northern", "Fleet", "and", "its", "command", "structure", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "August", "1959", ",", "Moore", "began", "using", "the", "jet-powered", "T-37", "in", "place", "of", "the", "T-28", "s", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "typescript", "memoirs", "are", "held", "at", "the", "University", "of", "California", ",", "Berkeley", ",", "Bancroft", "Library", "and", "contain", "comments", "on", "many", "of", "his", "faculty", "colleagues", "as", "well", "as", "the", "circumstances", "of", "his", "departure", "from", "the", "university", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["An", "Su-24M", "was", "shot", "down", "on", "3", "May", "1993", "with", "an", "FIM-92", "Stinger", "MANPADS", "fired", "by", "fundamentalists", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "later", "named", "after", "Hungarian", "amateur", "astronomer", "Jenő", "Gothard", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O"]}
{"text": ["Alternative", "rock", "musician", "Courtney", "Love", "has", "stated", "that", "her", "mother", ",", "Linda", "Carroll", ",", "named", "her", "after", "the", "protagonist", "of", "the", "novel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kaiser", "returned", "the", "award", "to", "Wheeler", "at", "a", "ceremony", "held", "at", "the", "Hollywood", "Roosevelt", "Hotel", "in", "1989", "."], "label": ["B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Their", "guilty", "verdicts", "were", "eventually", "reversed", "by", "the", "United", "States", "Supreme", "Court", "in", "its", "decision", "in", "``", "Moore", "v.", "Dempsey", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Two", "additional", "7.92", "mm", "(", ".312", "in", ")", "MG", "17s", "were", "mounted", "in", "the", "fuselage", "decking", "above", "the", "engine", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Couples", "without", "children", "can", "receive", "funding", "for", "IVF", "for", "up", "to", "two", "children", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-medical", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Corpus", "Christi", "IceRays", "are", "a", "Tier", "II", "junior", "ice", "hockey", "team", "playing", "in", "the", "North", "American", "Hockey", "League", "(", "NAHL", ")", "but", "are", "on", "hiatus", "for", "at", "least", "the", "2020–21", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "bridge", "shot", "in", "the", "Barry", "Levinson", "movie", ",", "``", "Diner", "``", ",", "at", "21:51", "in", "the", "movie", "used", "Fleet", "Street", "at", "S", "Newkirk", "St", "with", "the", "Crown", "Cork", "and", "Seal", "building", "in", "the", "background", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "was", "a", "reaction", "against", "the", "Christianization", "of", "the", "Roman", "Empire", "by", "Constantine", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "B-person-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "the", "Communist", "Party", "chairman", "Aksel", "Larsen", "was", "ousted", "from", "the", "party", "in", "1958", "Jespersen", "was", "named", "the", "new", "party", "chairman", "at", "the", "20th", "party", "congress", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty", "I-organization-politicalparty", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "access", "provided", "downloadable", "versions", "of", "hit", "games", "free", "to", "the", "user", "but", "required", "the", "user", "to", "download", "the", "games", "only", "at", "certain", "times", "through", "a", "TV", "antenna", ",", "in", "a", "fashion", "similar", "to", "recording", "a", "TV", "show", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["IJN", "I-159", "was", "laid", "down", "on", "5", "March", "1927", "at", "the", "Yokosuka", "Navy", "Yard", "."], "label": ["B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lisinopril", "/", "amlodipine", ",", "sold", "under", "the", "brand", "name", "Lisonorm", "among", "others", ",", "is", "a", "medication", "used", "to", "treat", "high", "blood", "pressure", "."], "label": ["B-other-medical", "O", "B-other-medical", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O"]}
{"text": ["Both", "houses", "of", "the", "state", "legislature", "passed", "the", "DeSalvio-Quinn", "Bill", "and", "in", "April", "1949", "Governor", "Thomas", "Dewey", "signed", "it", ",", "thus", "securing", "the", "protection", "of", "the", "site", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Subsequently", ",", "PIAS3", "was", "also", "found", "to", "be", "a", "regulator", "protein", "of", "other", "key", "transcription", "factors", ",", "including", "MITF", ",", "NFκB", ",", "SMAD", "and", "estrogen", "receptor", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "B-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "2002", "BAFTA", "Awards", ",", "director", "David", "Yates", "and", "producer", "Nigel", "Stafford-Clark", "collected", "an", "award", "for", "``", "The", "Way", "We", "Live", "Now", "``", ",", "which", "won", "``", "Best", "Drama", "Serial", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["All", "Class", "222", "units", "are", "maintained", "at", "the", "dedicated", "Derby", "Etches", "Park", "depot", ",", "just", "south", "of", "Derby", "railway", "station", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "second", "quarter", ",", "the", "Falcons", "regained", "the", "lead", "with", "kicker", "Morten", "Andersen", "getting", "a", "32-yard", "field", "goal", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "object", "is", "a", "G-type", "main-sequence", "star", "with", "a", "stellar", "classification", "of", "G7V", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "appear", "as", "two", "patches", "of", "haze", "with", "10x50", "binoculars", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "16", "January", "1997", ",", "Al-Fayed", "appeared", "in", "an", "edition", "of", "the", "``", "Dispatches", "``", "documentary", "series", "on", "Channel", "4", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "his", "time", "at", "MIT", ",", "he", "was", "briefly", "employed", "by", "the", "firm", "of", "Maginnis", "and", "Walsh", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "B-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "elections", ",", "Krosnick", "hypothesized", "the", "effect", "may", "be", "from", "voters", ",", "feeling", "compelled", "to", "cast", "a", "vote", ",", "choosing", "the", "first", "choice", "on", "the", "list", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "left", "just", "over", "a", "year", "later", "to", "re-join", "Millwall", "as", "assistant", "manager", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["R", "Leporis", "is", "too", "far", "from", "earth", "for", "its", "parallax", "to", "be", "measured", "effectively", ";", "Guandalini", "and", "Cristallo", "calculated", "the", "luminosity", "of", "Mira", "variables", "based", "on", "their", "periods", "."], "label": ["B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "O", "B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "5", "July", "2016", ",", "he", "was", "loaned", "to", "Olympiacos", "F.C", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "contiguous", "with", "the", "Colorado", "State", "Forest", "as", "well", "as", "the", "Arapaho", "National", "Forest", "and", "the", "Routt", "National", "Forest", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Platinum", "Pyramids", "``", "was", "mixed", "by", "John", "C.", "Adams", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2018", ",", "February", "7-April", "30", ",", "Hicks", "had", "a", "solo", "exhibition", "``", "Life", "Lines", "``", "at", "the", "Centre", "Pompidou", "which", "included", "more", "than", "100", "works", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "has", "contributed", "to", "UN", "peacekeeping", "efforts", "on", "the", "continent", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dobongsan", "Station", "is", "a", "subway", "station", "on", "the", "Seoul", "Subway", "Line", "1", "and", "Line", "7", "."], "label": ["B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "the", "four-year", "cycle", "of", "Principalship", "of", "the", "Samavesam", "of", "Telugu", "Baptist", "Churches", "ended", "in", "the", "academic", "year", "1989–1990", ",", "the", "Andhra", "Evangelical", "Lutheran", "Church", "'s", "cycle", "of", "Principalship", "began", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Eli", "Tomac", "dominated", "the", "450cc", "Main", "Event", "for", "his", "third", "win", "of", "the", "year", ",", "while", "Austin", "Forkner", "returned", "to", "his", "winning", "ways", "in", "the", "250cc", "Eastern", "Regional", "Main", "Event", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["All", "prices", "had", "to", "be", "indicated", "in", "both", "PLZ", "and", "PLN", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "B-other-currency", "O"]}
{"text": ["Both", "stars", "exhibit", "stellar", "flare", "activity", ",", "but", "the", "chromosphere", "of", "B", "is", "25", "%", "more", "active", "than", "for", "61", "Cygni", "A", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "October", "2009", ",", "Tele", "5", "launched", "a", "free", "live", "broadcast", "of", "its", "programme", "on", "the", "internet", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "CPP", "is", "headed", "by", "François", "Lucas", "Sainvil", "of", "Lespwa", "and", "has", "been", "characterized", "as", "leftist", ",", "populistic", "and", "anti-neoliberal", "in", "the", "press", "."], "label": ["O", "B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Under", "the", "California", "Constitution", ",", "the", "Governor", "serves", "a", "four-year", "term", ",", "with", "a", "maximum", "limit", "of", "two", "consecutive", "terms", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1976", ",", "he", "attended", "a", "senior", "management", "course", "at", "Harvard", "University", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "is", "achieved", "through", "running", "Mac", "OS", "9", "without", "access", "to", "its", "Finder", "inside", "OS", "X", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "I-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "O"]}
{"text": ["Choline", "acyltransferase", "is", "the", "enzyme", "that", "synthesizes", "acetylcholine", "and", "is", "often", "used", "as", "a", "marker", "in", "research", "relating", "to", "acetylcholine", "production", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "film", "was", "released", "on", "August", "9", ",", "1925", ",", "by", "Universal", "Pictures", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["RFRA", "is", "constitutional", "as", "applied", "to", "the", "Federal", "government", ",", "as", "seen", "in", "``", "Gonzales", "v.", "O", "Centro", "Espirita", "Beneficente", "Uniao", "do", "Vegetal", "``", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "compatriot", "Mary", "Jepkosgei", "Keitany", "claimed", "the", "women", "'s", "division", "with", "a", "time", "of", "2:24:25", ",", "her", "second", "consecutive", "win", "in", "New", "York", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", "are", "at", "least", "40", "named", "and", "hundreds", "of", "unnamed", "glaciers", "in", "Denali", "National", "Park", "and", "Preserve", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "1970s", ",", "the", "PKK", "was", "involved", "in", "urban", "warfare", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "the", "East", "Slavic", "forms", "have", "tended", "to", "be", "used", "exclusively", "in", "the", "various", "dialects", "that", "are", "experiencing", "a", "rapid", "decline", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Potential", "applications", "for", "this", "research", "include", "blood", "glucose", "monitoring", "systems", "to", "help", "manage", "diabetes", "mellitus", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O"]}
{"text": ["Unfortunately", ",", "when", "he", "attempted", "to", "take", "on", "a", "number", "of", "locals", "to", "replenish", "his", "crew", "he", "discovered", "they", "were", "infected", "with", "lycanthropy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "the", "youngest", "NHK", "Cup", "winner", "at", "20", "years", "and", "11", "months", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "released", "his", "last", "album", ",", "Phone", "Call", "From", "The", "Devil", ",", "in", "1975", "on", "Scorpion", "Records", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["One", "By", "Two", "is", "a", "1993", "Telugu", "comedy", "film", "directed", "by", "Shiva", "Nageswara", "Rao", "."], "label": ["B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "I-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["Trí", "lived", "lavishly", "and", "flamboyantly", ",", "leading", "to", "suspicions", "of", "corruption", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "also", "acted", "in", "``", "The", "Vagina", "Monologues", "``", "at", "Sydney", "'s", "Ensemble", "Theatre", "and", "starred", "in", "``", "Closer", "``", "for", "the", "Darlinghurst", "Theatre", "Company", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O"]}
{"text": ["Canada", "recovered", "to", "defeat", "Guatemala", "in", "the", "third-place", "playoff", ",", "a", "rematch", "of", "their", "first", "round", "game", ",", "winning", "on", "penalties", "(", "5–3", ")", "after", "a", "scoreless", "draw", "through", "120", "minutes", "."], "label": ["B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "ineffective", "and", "was", "repealed", "20", "years", "later", "by", "the", "Ecclesiastical", "Titles", "Act", "1871", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "caused", "unrest", "in", "the", "area", ",", "which", "Ahmed", "joined", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Strip", "is", "known", "for", "its", "concentration", "of", "casinos", "and", "resort", "hotels", ",", "including", "the", "43-story", "Mandalay", "Bay", "southwest", "of", "its", "intersection", "with", "Mandalay", "Bay", "Road", ",", "in", "the", "unincorporated", "town", "of", "Paradise", "."], "label": ["O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "an", "extension", "to", "Darwen", "Library", ",", "hence", "the", "name", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "won", "this", "3FM", "serious", "talent", "award", "on", "April", "8", ",", "2014", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Examples", "include", "the", "fictional", "Rascal", "&", "amp", ";", "Cottonwood", "route", "from", "All", "Aboard", "and", "packs", "of", "the", "LMS", "Jubilees", "and", "the", "GWR", "4900", "Class", "locomotives", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-car", "I-product-car", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "sometimes", "used", "off-label", "for", "the", "treatment", "of", "fibromyalgia", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Dolly", "Teen", "Choice", "Awards", "were", "established", "in", "2006", "by", "``", "Dolly", "Magazine", "``", "o", "honour", "achievements", "in", "music", ",", "fashion", ",", "sport", ",", "television", "and", "media", "personalities", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Thus", ",", "the", "first", "few", "names", ",", "of", "Vishnu", "sahasranama", ",", "in", "particular", ",", "do", "not", "describe", "features", "of", "Vishnu", "in", "detail", "and", "hence", "are", "not", "anthropomorphic", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Attendance", "stats", "are", "calculated", "by", "averaging", "each", "team", "'s", "self-reported", "home", "attendances", "from", "the", "historical", "match", "archive", "at", "United", "Soccer", "Leagues", "(", "USL", ")", ",", "and", "then", "averaging", "this", "league-wide", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "manuscript", "is", "currently", "housed", "at", "the", "Sackler", "Library", "(", "Papyrology", "Rooms", ",", "P.", "Oxy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "peak", "in", "the", "West-Central", "Alaska", "Range", "is", "also", "named", "in", "his", "honor", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "treaty", "brought", "an", "end", "to", "the", "conflict", "commonly", "known", "as", "the", "First", "Peloponnesian", "War", ",", "which", "had", "been", "raging", "since", "c.", "460", "BCE", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "noted", "for", "his", "performance", "of", "the", "song", "'", "You", "'re", "in", "Vegas", "'", "which", "is", "available", "for", "download", "on", "iTunes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O"]}
{"text": ["These", "neurodegenerative", "diseases", "are", "commonly", "called", "``", "prion", "diseases", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Portuguese", "merchants", "and", "settlers", "started", "to", "mix", "with", "locals", "almost", "immediately", "."], "label": ["B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "a", "``", "repacker", "``", "tool", "was", "planned", "for", "the", "next", "Reiser4", "file", "system", "to", "deal", "with", "file", "fragmentation", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "smaller", "cousin", "Rhinog", "Fach", "lies", "to", "the", "south", ",", "separated", "by", "the", "pass", "of", "Bwlch", "Drws", "Ardudwy", ",", "while", "its", "other", "neighbour", ",", "Moel", "Ysgyfarnogod", "lies", "to", "the", "north", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sikkim", "has", "75", "Buddhist", "monasteries", ",", "the", "oldest", "dating", "back", "to", "the", "1700s", "."], "label": ["B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Western", "fast", "food", "chains", "such", "as", "McDonald", "'s", ",", "Wendy", "'s", ",", "KFC", ",", "and", "Pizza", "Hut", "are", "a", "common", "sight", "in", "the", "country", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "voted", "Most", "Promising", "Playwright", "of", "1981", "by", "The", "Financial", "Times", "and", "The", "Morning", "Star", "for", "his", "first", "stage", "play", "Blood", "On", "The", "Dole", "which", "was", "performed", "at", "The", "Liverpool", "Playhouse", "in", "1981", "where", "he", "was", "resident", "playwright", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "siege", "included", "the", "use", "of", "artillery", "to", "try", "to", "breach", "the", "walls", "but", "the", "garrison", "was", "finally", "relieved", "by", "an", "English", "army", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2005", ",", "the", "Center", "for", "the", "Study", "of", "Confucian", "Religion", "was", "established", "and", "``", "guoxue", "''", "(", "``", "national", "learning", "''", ")", "started", "to", "be", "implemented", "in", "public", "schools", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "November", "1967", ",", "five", "months", "after", "the", "introduction", "of", "the", "Malaysian", "dollar", ",", "the", "pound", "was", "devalued", "by", "14.3", "%", ",", "leading", "to", "a", "collapse", "in", "confidence", "for", "the", "sterling", "area", "and", "its", "demise", "in", "1972", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", "to", "careful", "screening", "of", "donors", ",", "each", "batch", "of", "milk", "is", "tested", "for", "bacterial", "counts", "before", "pasteurization", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["1", "record", "(", "``", "Ai", "n't", "Nobody", "Here", "but", "Us", "Chickens", "``", ")", "and", "five", "of", "the", "top", "ten", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Gamle", "Ole", "``", "is", "traditionally", "paired", "with", "some", "rings", "of", "raw", "onion", "and", "a", "slice", "of", "meat", "aspic", "on", "a", "slice", "of", "bread", "for", "an", "open", "face", "sandwich", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Buzzard", "was", "developed", "by", "scaling-up", "the", "Rolls-Royce", "Kestrel", "Engine", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "herbal", "tea", "called", "Labrador", "tea", "(", "not", "a", "true", "tea", ")", "is", "made", "from", "one", "of", "three", "closely", "related", "species", ":"], "label": ["O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "character", "quickly", "made", "him", "a", "master", "of", "the", "Bible", "and", "basic", "Christian", "mysteries", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "FAE", "flew", "a", "total", "of", "179", "combat", "missions", "with", "A-37B", "and", "Mirage", "F-1", "aircraft", "to", "counter", "these", "attacks", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "the", "split", "with", "the", "Baháʼís", ",", "some", "Azalis", "were", "very", "active", "in", "secular", "reform", "movements", "and", "the", "Iranian", "Constitutional", "Revolution", "(", "1905–1907", ")", ",", "including", "Shaykh", "Ahmad", "Ruhi", "Kermani", "and", "Mirza", "Abd-al-Hosayn", "Kermani", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O"]}
{"text": ["If", "the", "race", "is", "delayed", "to", "a", "Monday", ",", "the", "Hollywood", "Hotel", "studio", "is", "usually", "not", "used", ",", "with", "the", "exception", "of", "the", "2012", "Daytona", "500", ",", "which", "was", "delayed", "by", "one", "day", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", ",", "Kimball", "suffered", "a", "painful", "thigh", "wound", "that", "put", "him", "out", "of", "action", "for", "the", "winter", "and", "spring", "of", "1863", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["200", "were", "carried", "by", "sea", "in", "five", "ships", "under", "Laubière", ",", "200", "advanced", "by", "land", "around", "Mount", "Pelée", "and", "200", "by", "Morne", "des", "Gommiers", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "battalion", "played", "a", "major", "role", "in", "the", "Battle", "of", "Hue", "during", "February", "1968", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "of", "May", "2013", ",", "there", "are", "62", "contracting", "parties", "to", "the", "Strasbourg", "Agreement", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["Opera", "San", "Luis", "Obispo", "is", "currently", "involved", "in", "their", "eighth", "consecutive", "Citywide", "Arts", "Collaboration", ":", "``", "Madama", "Butterfly", "''", ",", "scheduled", "for", "October", "2016", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "unconfirmed", "planet", "Gliese", "581", "g", "is", "another", "good", "candidate", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Two", "improved", "``", "Sovremenny", "``", "class", "vessels", "were", "acquired", "in", "2002", ",", "and", "include", "a", "longer", "range", "SS-N-22", "missile", ",", "improved", "air", "defense", "missiles", ",", "and", "the", "Kashtan", "CIWS", "cannon", "and", "missile", "combination", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Anglesey", "section", "was", "financed", "through", "a", "Private", "Finance", "Initiative", "scheme", "."], "label": ["O", "B-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Further", "influence", "by", "Mandarin", "occurred", "after", "the", "overthrow", "of", "the", "Qing", "Dynasty", "in", "1912", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "number", "of", "other", "minority", "languages", "is", "large", "with", "approximately", "20", "nationalities", "residing", "in", "Nagu", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "took", "place", "at", "the", "Rio", "All", "Suite", "Hotel", "and", "Casino", "from", "July", "29", "to", "31", ",", "utilizing", "a", "ballroom", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bifidobacterium", "have", "a", "metabolic", "pathway", "for", "the", "uptake", "and", "digestion", "of", "specific", "human", "milk", "oligosaccharides", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Class", "was", "fully", "withdrawn", "as", "a", "result", "of", "the", "arrival", "of", "new", "Class", "90", "locomotives", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["5–0", "and", "clinch", "their", "seventh", "consecutive", "S", "uper", "League", "Greece", "title", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "use", "of", "flambé", "can", "retain", "as", "much", "as", "75", "%", "of", "the", "alcohol", "in", "the", "brandy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "also", "served", "as", "an", "American", "Civil", "War", "army", "post", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pluto", "sought", "to", "create", "a", "``", "nether-hole", "''", "that", "would", "destroy", "the", "universe", "."], "label": ["B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "made", "her", "acting", "debut", "as", "a", "child", "actress", "in", "a", "bit", "part", "in", "``", "Dear", "Ends", "``", "(", "1993", ")", ",", "``", "Summer", "Showers", "``", "(", "1995", ")", "and", "``", "Star", "in", "My", "Heart", "``", "(", "1997", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "main", "library", "includes", "a", "Louisiana", "Division", "that", "houses", "city", "archives", "and", "special", "collections", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "January", "1951", ",", "was", "unable", "to", "call", "at", "the", "Cocos", "Islands", "to", "collect", "mail", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Following", "the", "introduction", "of", "the", "Local", "Governance", "(", "Scotland", ")", "Act", "2004", "local", "elections", "are", "held", "using", "the", "single", "transferable", "vote", ",", "with", "this", "taking", "place", "for", "the", "first", "time", "in", "2007", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "film", "``", "National", "Lampoon", "'s", "Animal", "House", "``", "(", "1978", ")", "was", "filmed", "on", "the", "university", "campus", "and", "the", "surrounding", "area", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "last", "film", "role", "was", "eight", "years", "later", "in", "``", "Year", "of", "the", "Comet", "``", "(", "1992", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Alpha", "3", "``", "further", "expanded", "the", "playable", "fighter", "roster", "from", "``", "Street", "Fighter", "Alpha", "2", "``", "and", "added", "new", "features", "such", "as", "selectable", "fighting", "styles", "called", "``", "isms", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["29", "on", "``", "Entertainment", "Weekly", "``", "s", "list", "of", "the", "50", "best", "high", "school", "movies", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "the", "evening", "of", "28", "April", "2019", ",", "Gatwick", "Airport", "had", "to", "close", "temporarily", "due", "to", "an", "unconfirmed", "sighting", "of", "a", "drone", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Miglustat", "is", "an", "iminosugar", ",", "a", "synthetic", "analogue", "of", "-glucose", "and", "a", "white", "to", "off-white", "crystalline", "solid", "that", "has", "a", "bitter", "taste", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "the", "spiritual", "successor", "to", "``", "U.N.", "Squadron", "``", ",", "which", "was", "released", "in", "the", "previous", "year", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "freight", "train", "was", "led", "by", "two", "EMD", "SD70ACe", "locomotives", ",", "#", "8485", "and", "8491", ",", "and", "was", "pulling", "17", "freight", "cars", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", "to", "this", "it", "also", "had", "fiction", ",", "news", "and", "a", "Rumours", "section", "based", "on", "the", "format", "of", "the", "RuneQuest", "supplements", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Further", "east", "across", "the", "Cebu", "Strait", "is", "the", "island", "of", "Bohol", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Beatles", "and", "the", "Platters", "were", "also", "an", "important", "influence", "on", "Clube", "da", "Esquina", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O"]}
{"text": ["Beside", "that", ",", "the", "airport", "group", "owns", "35", "%", "of", "Hobart", "Airport", "and", "1", "%", "of", "Vienna", "International", "Airport", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Amazing", "Adult", "Fantasy", "``", "premiered", "with", "issue", "#", "7", ",", "taking", "over", "the", "numbering", "from", "``", "Amazing", "Adventures", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "was", "the", "nation", "'s", "first", "female", "head", "librarian", "at", "the", "Minneapolis", "Public", "Library", "from", "1904", "to", "1936", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Serving", "seasonal", "dishes", ",", "the", "Daily", "Dose", "sources", "the", "ingredients", "that", "are", "locally", "grown", "and", "harvested", "by", "regional", "farms", ",", "farmer", "'s", "markets", ",", "and", "bakeries", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Aaj", "TV", "administration", "canceled", "3", "Idiots", "after", "airing", "its", "last", "episode", "on", "10", "March", "2012", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "also", "a", "member", "of", "the", "Sutton", "Thomas", "Band", "prior", "to", "joining", "Skid", "Row", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "sequel", ",", "``", "Star", "Wars", "Battlefront", "II", "``", ",", "was", "released", "on", "November", "17", ",", "2017", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "keeping", "with", "the", "conventions", "of", "the", "times", ",", "when", "the", "Negresco", "opened", "in", "1913", "its", "front", "opened", "on", "the", "side", "opposite", "the", "Mediterranean", "Sea", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O"]}
{"text": ["Chris", "'", "mother", "abandoned", "them", "when", "he", "was", "one", "years", "old", "."], "label": ["B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Virginia", "Beach", "Sportsplex", "stadium", "is", "located", "within", "the", "community", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "1:10", "scale", "``", "Titanic", "``", "model", "was", "one", "of", "the", "main", "attractions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["An", "untitled", "``", "Queen", "of", "Babble", "``", "movie", "is", "currently", "``", "in", "development", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "principle", ",", "every", "Christian", "has", "the", "power", "to", "command", "demons", "and", "drive", "them", "out", "in", "the", "name", "of", "Christ", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "next", "year", "he", "was", "transferred", "to", "the", "USS", "Nevada", "(", "BB-36", ")", "and", "was", "promoted", "to", "Lieutenant", ",", "Junior", "Grade", "in", "the", "summer", "of", "1931", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "wave", "arrived", "at", "the", "cove", "following", "the", "1946", "Aleutian", "Islands", "earthquake", "and", "a", "wave", "arrived", "after", "the", "1964", "Alaska", "earthquake", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "mid-1990s", ",", "he", "oversaw", "the", "creation", "of", "Disney", "'s", "Wide", "World", "of", "Sports", "Complex", ",", "a", "state-of-the-art", "multi-sport", "facility", "that", "opened", "on", "March", "28", ",", "1997", "and", "hosts", "more", "than", "180", "athletic", "events", "annually", "in", "some", "30", "sports", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "abdicated", "on", "22", "November", "1918", ",", "amidst", "the", "tumults", "of", "the", "German", "Revolution", "of", "1918–19", "which", "resulted", "in", "the", "abolition", "of", "the", "Grand", "Duchy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Until", "this", "link", "opened", "in", "1997", ",", "Lantau", "Island", "could", "only", "be", "accessed", "by", "water", ",", "and", "was", "completely", "rural", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "this", "book", "they", "assumed", "that", "the", "left-wing", "rioters", "of", "May", "68", "were", "totalitarian", "stalinists", ",", "and", "psychoanalyzed", "them", "saying", "that", "they", "were", "affected", "by", "a", "sordid", "infantilism", "caught", "up", "in", "an", "Oedipal", "revolt", "against", "the", "Father", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Patterson", "Field", "``", "in", "the", "south-east", "opened", "in", "1942", "despite", "being", "partly", "incomplete", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "La", "Vicaría", "``", "exemplifies", "genre", "painting", "of", "the", "19th", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Convocation", "Center", "is", "a", "multi-purpose", "arena", "that", "opened", "on", "December", "9", ",", "1998", "is", "the", "largest", "indoor", "facility", "."], "label": ["B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Civic", "Center", "includes", "4,806", "permanent", "arena", "seats", "focused", "on", "an", "ice", "hockey/basketball-type", "arena", ",", "but", "it", "can", "accommodate", "up", "to", "7,800", "people", "for", "concerts", "and", "other", "events", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["One", "big", "event", "that", "made", "the", "criticism", "even", "stronger", "was", "Hurricane", "David", "that", "hit", "in", "1979", ",", "which", "slowed", "the", "economy", "even", "more", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Between", "1943", "and", "1955", "the", "whole", "class", "was", "rebuilt", "to", "create", "the", "LMS", "Rebuilt", "Royal", "Scot", "Class", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O"]}
{"text": ["Initially", ",", "it", "was", "suspected", "that", "the", "accident", "was", "due", "to", "the", "effect", "of", "Xangsane", ",", "but", "it", "was", "later", "discovered", "that", "the", "accident", "was", "due", "to", "a", "pilot", "error", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "force", "is", "best", "known", "for", "the", "unlawful", "killing", "of", "over", "90", "people", "in", "the", "Hillsborough", "Disaster", "and", "the", "systematic", "ignoring", "of", "child", "rape", "in", "the", "2000", "'s", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "show", "presents", "a", "school", "uprising", "similar", "to", "the", "Soweto", "uprising", "on", "16", "June", "1976", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "third", "round", "draw", "was", "conducted", "at", "Easter", "Road", "Stadium", "on", "Thursday", "29", "August", "2013", "at", "11:30am", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "accidental", "discovery", "of", "her", "intact", "tomb", "during", "the", "Hungarian", "Revolution", "of", "1848", "has", "provided", "an", "opportunity", "for", "patriotic", "demonstrations", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "unusual", "for", "a", "``", "menologion", "``", "from", "that", "era", "to", "be", "so", "richly", "painted", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
