{"text": ["The", "contagion", "arrived", "in", "Roman", "Egypt", "in", "541", ",", "spread", "around", "the", "Mediterranean", "Sea", "until", "544", ",", "and", "persisted", "in", "Northern", "Europe", "and", "the", "Arabian", "Peninsula", ",", "until", "549", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "``", "Phoenix", "New", "Times", "``", "wrote", "that", "Huff", "'s", "vocal", "stylings", "were", "``", "a", "perfect", "contrast", "to", "the", "rhythmically", "ebullient", "programmed", "synths", "and", "beats", "supporting", "them", "-", "backdrops", "coursing", ",", "playful", ",", "robotic", ",", "and", "pop", "basic", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Denver", "Pavilions", "is", "a", "shopping", "mall", "located", "on", "the", "16th", "Street", "Mall", "in", "Downtown", "Denver", ",", "Colorado", "."], "label": ["B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["Åre", "Östersund", "Airport", "and", "Trondheim", "Airport", ",", "Værnes", ",", "are", "the", "closest", "international", "airports", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Panyassis", "wrote", "of", "him", "as", "father", "of", "Triptolemus", ",", "adding", "that", "``", "Demeter", "came", "to", "him", "''", ";", "this", "version", "of", "the", "myth", "is", "found", "in", "the", "works", "of", "Hyginus", "and", "Servius", "."], "label": ["B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O"]}
{"text": ["Also", "in", "Enerhodar", ",", "is", "the", "Zaporizhzhia", "Thermal", "Power", "Station", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "chemical", "terms", ",", "the", "pozzolanic", "reaction", "occurs", "between", "calcium", "hydroxide", ",", "also", "known", "as", "portlandite", "(", "Ca", "(", "OH", ")", "2", ")", ",", "and", "silicic", "acid", "(", "written", "as", "H4SiO4", ",", "or", "Si", "(", "OH", ")", "4", ",", "in", "the", "geochemical", "notation", ")", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "control", "method", "was", "chosen", "because", "the", "Taurus", "was", "intended", "to", "be", "played", "by", "foot", "while", "the", "player", "'s", "hands", "played", "one", "or", "more", "keyboards", ",", "although", "it", "was", "often", "used", "by", "guitarists", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Presidential", "Records", "Act", "mandates", "the", "preservation", "of", "all", "presidential", "records", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "high", "level", "of", "STAT3", "was", "described", "in", "isolated", "CSCs", "from", "liver", ",", "bone", ",", "cervical", "and", "brain", "cancer", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Ground-penetrating", "radar", "instruments", "on", "the", "Mars", "Express", "orbiter", "(", "MARSIS", ")", "and", "the", "Mars", "Reconnaissance", "Orbiter", "(", "SHARAD", ")", "are", "currently", "providing", "stunning", "echo-return", "data", "on", "subsurface", "materials", "and", "structures", "to", "depths", "of", "up", "to", "5", "km", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "second", "attack", "utilized", "a", "truck", "modified", "to", "include", "an", "evaporation", "system", "based", "on", "heating", "sarin", "over", "a", "gas", "stove", "fire", ";", "despite", "prior", "warnings", "from", "cult", "member", "Kazuyoshi", "Takizawa", ",", "the", "truck", "caught", "fire", "during", "the", "dissemination", ",", "severely", "poisoning", "the", "driver", "Tomomitsu", "Niimi", "and", "causing", "both", "Niimi", "and", "Murai", "–", "the", "operators", "–", "to", "flee", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "O", "B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Per", "Constitution", "of", "India", ",", "Meitei", "language", "is", "among", "the", "languages", "specified", "in", "the", "Schedule", "VIII", "of", "the", "Constitution", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "normal", "WAS", "z/OS", "SMF", "120", "subtype", "9", "record", "(", "or", "120.9", "in", "shorthand", "notation", ")", "was", "used", "to", "capture", "the", "inbound", "call", "information", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "I-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sigurlaug", "enrolled", "into", "the", "medical", "department", "of", "the", "University", "of", "Iceland", "and", "graduated", "as", "a", "Medical", "Doctor", "in", "2010", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-educationaldegree", "I-other-educationaldegree", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Uranus", "governs", "societies", ",", "clubs", ",", "and", "any", "group", "based", "on", "humanitarian", "or", "progressive", "ideals", "."], "label": ["B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Covering", "a", "total", "of", "10", "acres", "(", "4", "ha", ")", "adjacent", "to", "the", "John", "F.", "Kennedy", "Center", "for", "the", "Performing", "Arts", ",", "the", "buildings", "include", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["(", "Early", "Frisch", "'s", "menus", "show", "that", "he", "used", "tartar", "sauce", "on", "hamburgers", "and", "cheeseburgers", ",", "but", "mayonnaise", "on", "his", "Big", "Boy", "hamburgers", ".", ")"], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "March", "2008", ",", "the", "program", "was", "rebranded", "as", "``", "America", "'s", "Election", "Headquarters", "``", "during", "the", "2008", "presidential", "election", "campaign", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "the", "trestle", "over", "the", "Southern", "Pacific", "Railroad", ",", "bridge", "beams", "were", "fashioned", "out", "of", "used", "Southern", "Pacific", "turntables", ",", "and", "timbers", "were", "reused", "from", "those", "ferry", "moles", "no", "longer", "in", "use", "due", "to", "the", "Bay", "Bridge", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", "is", "a", "101-room", "Hilton", "Garden", "Inn", "on", "university-owned", "land", "adjacent", "to", "the", "field", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "late", "1980s", "saw", "NEPA", "initiating", "the", "organization", "of", "the", "Freedom", "from", "Debt", "Coalition", "(", "FDC", ")", "and", "the", "Movement", "for", "Nationalist", "Industrialization", "(", "MNI", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Also", "in", "the", "Puerto", "Rican", "roster", "were", "Jim", "Gilliam", "(", "2B", ")", ",", "Buster", "Clarkson", "(", "3B", ")", ",", "Bob", "Thurman", "(", "OF", ")", "and", "Willard", "Brown", "(", "OF", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Artists", "removed", "the", "plywood", "covering", "the", "building", "'s", "entrance", "and", "entered", "the", "space", "furnished", "with", "artworks", "and", "supplies", ",", "turning", "the", "abandoned", "residence", "hotel", "into", "a", "temporary", "museum", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "area", "became", "the", "Kai", "Tak", "Airport", "which", "has", "now", "been", "demolished", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Rigvedic", "God", "of", "storms", "Rudra", "presided", "over", "the", "star", ";", "this", "association", "was", "linked", "by", "19th-century", "star", "enthusiast", "to", "Orion", "'s", "stormy", "nature", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Wendy", "'s", "Co", ".", "has", "been", "looking", "to", "remodel", "existing", "stores", "and", "upgrade", "the", "curb", "appeal", "of", "its", "locations", "."], "label": ["B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["equivalent", ")", "from", "the", "Law", "Faculty", "of", "the", "National", "and", "Kapodistrian", "University", "of", "Athens", "and", "a", "Master", "of", "Laws", "(", "LL.M", ".", ")"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "B-other-educationaldegree", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Today", ",", "that", "building", "is", "the", "only", "surviving", "portion", "of", "the", "original", "Wardman", "Park", ",", "known", "as", "the", "Wardman", "Tower", "and", "is", "listed", "in", "the", "National", "Register", "of", "Historic", "Places", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "renamed", "in", "memory", "of", "the", "seven", "astronauts", "who", "died", "when", "the", "Space", "Shuttle", "``", "Challenger", "``", "disintegrated", "shortly", "after", "liftoff", "on", "January", "28", ",", "1986", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["To", "allow", "the", "playoffs", "to", "be", "held", "in", "their", "entirety", ",", "in", "October", "the", "NFL", "rescheduled", "Super", "Bowl", "XXXVI", "at", "the", "Louisiana", "Superdome", "from", "27", "January", "2002", "to", "3", "February", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Connelly", "started", "as", "a", "roadie", "for", "thrash", "metal", "band", "Anthrax", "where", "he", "became", "a", "close", "friend", "of", "Anthrax", "bassist", "Danny", "Lilker", "."], "label": ["B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "papers", "are", "held", "at", "the", "Knight", "Library", "at", "the", "University", "of", "Oregon", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "were", "also", "featured", "on", "the", "soundtrack", "for", "Troma", "'s", "Citizen", "Toxie", ":", "The", "Toxic", "Avenger", "IV", "which", "was", "released", "in", "2000", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Puebla", "lost", "the", "first", "match", "played", "in", "Estadio", "Jalisco", "1–0", "."], "label": ["B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "founded", "in", "1881", ",", "and", "was", "known", "in", "its", "early", "years", "as", "the", "``", "Phoenix", "Evening", "Gazette", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "started", "playing", "for", "the", "Waikato", "/", "Bay", "of", "Plenty", "Magic", "in", "1998", "and", "in", "2000", "was", "appointed", "captain", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Normal", "hemoglobin", "levels", "correlate", "with", "the", "person", "'s", "age", "and", "sex", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sinclair", "served", "as", "Colonial", "Secretary", "under", "FitzRoy", "(", "until", "18", "November", "1845", ")", ",", "George", "Grey", "(", "18", "November", "1845", "–", "3", "January", "1854", ")", ",", "acting", "Governor", "Robert", "Wynyard", "(", "3", "January", "1854", "–", "6", "September", "1855", ")", "and", "Thomas", "Gore", "Browne", "(", "from", "6", "September", "1855", ")", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sea", "devils", "are", "the", "family", "of", "deep-sea", "anglerfish", "known", "as", "the", "Ceratiidae", ",", "from", "the", "Greek", "``", "keras", "''", ",", "``", "horn", "''", ",", "referring", "to", "the", "bioluminescent", "lure", "that", "projects", "from", "the", "fishes", "'", "forehead", "."], "label": ["B-other-livingthing", "I-other-livingthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-livingthing", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lowndes", "won", "Best", "Actress", "in", "a", "Leading", "Role", "at", "the", "2003", "Manchester", "Evening", "News", "Theatre", "Awards", "for", "productions", "of", "``", "Port", "``", "and", "``", "The", "Seagull", "``", "at", "the", "Royal", "Exchange", "Theatre", "."], "label": ["B-person-actor", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O"]}
{"text": ["Since", "2008", ",", "The", "Chicago", "Country", "Music", "Festival", "was", "held", "simultaneously", "with", "the", "Taste", "of", "Chicago", "but", "now", "has", "its", "own", "two-day", "festival", ",", "typically", "held", "in", "the", "fall", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "airplane", "was", "a", "Curtiss", "SB2C", "Helldiver", "that", "had", "ditched", "in", "the", "reservoir", "because", "of", "engine", "failure", "while", "conducting", "dive", "bombing", "practice", "toward", "the", "end", "of", "World", "War", "II", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O"]}
{"text": ["National", "and", "international", "tournaments", "are", "usually", "hosted", "by", "member", "clubs", "but", "managed", "directly", "by", "the", "WFAA", "General", "Committee", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "album", "was", "nominated", "as", "the", "Best", "Jazz", "Album", "at", "the", "1990", "ARIA", "Awards", "but", "lost", "out", "to", "Browne", ",", "Costello", "&", "amp", ";", "Grabowsky", "with", "their", "album", "``", "Six", "By", "Three", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["All", "crew", "members", "were", "based", "at", "Los", "Angeles", "International", "Airport", "with", "maintenance", "and", "gate", "facilities", "provided", "by", "TWA", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["Seats", "and", "the", "interior", "design", "were", "adapted", "to", "the", "ICE", "3", "design", ",", "electric", "sockets", "were", "added", "to", "every", "seat", ",", "the", "audio", "and", "video", "entertainment", "systems", "were", "removed", "and", "electronic", "seat", "reservation", "indicators", "were", "added", "above", "the", "seats", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "June", "14", ",", "1968", ",", "the", "1.4", "km", "diameter", "asteroid", "1566", "Icarus", "passed", "Earth", "at", "a", "distance", "of", ",", "or", "16", "times", "the", "distance", "of", "the", "Moon", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["Thomas", "Aquinas", "belonged", "to", "the", "Dominican", "Order", "(", "formally", "``", "Ordo", "Praedicatorum", "''", ",", "the", "Order", "of", "Preachers", ")", "who", "began", "as", "an", "order", "dedicated", "to", "the", "conversion", "of", "the", "Albigensians", "and", "other", "heterodox", "factions", ",", "at", "first", "by", "peaceful", "means", ";", "later", "the", "Albigensians", "were", "dealt", "with", "by", "means", "of", "the", "Albigensian", "Crusade", "."], "label": ["B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "the", "BBC", "'s", "response", "to", "ITV", "'s", "successful", "series", "``", "The", "Sweeney", "``", ",", "but", "received", "criticism", "for", "its", "levels", "of", "violence", "and", "lasted", "for", "just", "two", "seasons", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "name", "in", "Italian", "--", "''", "Desiderio", "''", "--", "directly", "translates", "to", "``", "desire", "''", "in", "English", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "extension", "would", "use", "South", "19th", "Street", "and", "stop", "at", "six", "stations", ",", "carrying", "approximately", "18,000", "daily", "riders", "and", "costing", "up", "to", "$", "478", "million", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "monument", "is", "feet", "away", "from", "the", "grave", "of", "fellow", "MI6", "agent", "Commander", "Lionel", "Crabb", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O"]}
{"text": ["Most", "of", "these", "confrontations", "and", "speakings", "to", "high-ranking", "figures", "proved", "to", "be", "successful", "endeavors", ";", "religious", "dignitaries", "such", "as", "Epiphanius", "had", "wide-ranging", "influence", "on", "the", "rulers", "and", "aristocrats", "during", "this", "period", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "format", "of", "the", "newer", "show", "has", "been", "successfully", "exported", "to", "other", "countries", "as", "``", "Dancing", "with", "the", "Stars", "``", "or", "similar", "names", "in", "local", "languages", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Director", "Sidney", "J.", "Furie", "keeps", "them", "in", "the", "foreground", ",", "but", "uses", "slightly", "off-kilter", "angles", "to", "make", "his", "very", "ordinary", "settings", "creepy", "and", "cramped", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Research", "proposes", "patients", "with", "bipolar", "disorder", "show", "more", "common", "implicit", "and", "depressive", "self-referencing", "than", "unipolar", "patients", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", ")", ",", "and", "Joanna", "Kerns", "(", "``", "Growing", "Pains", "``", ")"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor", "I-person-actor", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "makes", "KBS", "only", "the", "world", "’", "s", "second", "broadcaster", "to", "have", "a", "broadcast", "programme", "on", "the", "prestigious", "list", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pedaliu", "co-edits", "with", "Professor", "John", "W.", "Young", "the", "Palgrave/Macmillan", "book", "series", ",", "Security", "Conflict", "and", "Cooperation", "in", "the", "Contemporary", "World", "(", "https", ":", "//www.palgrave.com/gp/series/14489", ")", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "received", "an", "honorary", "degree", "of", "Doctor", "of", "Education", "from", "the", "University", "of", "Bath", "in", "2015", "to", "mark", "her", "achievements", "as", "a", "longstanding", "and", "influential", "supporter", "of", "inspiring", "young", "people", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-educationaldegree", "I-other-educationaldegree", "I-other-educationaldegree", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["That", "remained", "the", "position", "until", "the", "aforementioned", "acts", "were", "repealed", "by", "the", "Visiting", "Forces", "Act", "1952", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["HP", "is", "also", "selling", "the", "Radia", "Client", "Automation", "products", "from", "Persistent", "."], "label": ["B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "I-product-software", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["That", "same", "year", ",", "he", "won", "the", "Grabby", "Award", "for", "Hottest", "Bottom", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "operation", "was", "given", "the", "codename", "FLINTOCK", ",", "permitting", "the", "assembly", "of", "sufficient", "combat", "shipping", "to", "accommodate", "two", "divisions", ",", "and", "all", "participating", "ships", ",", "aircraft", "and", "ground", "elements", "increased", "preparations", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "moderate", "doses", ",", "caffeine", "has", "been", "associated", "with", "reduced", "symptoms", "of", "depression", "and", "lower", "suicide", "risk", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "that", "time", "period", ",", "Walentyna", "Janta-Połczyński", "continued", "to", "supplement", "her", "initial", "gift", "with", "new", "materials", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["TPH1", "is", "expressed", "in", "the", "body", ",", "but", "not", "the", "brain", "."], "label": ["B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["SOIL", ":", "Is", "rich", "dark", "alluvial", "friable", "and", "fertile", "loam", "about", "deep", ",", "resting", "on", "a", "gravel", "bed", ",", "providing", "good", "draining", "–", "liable", "to", "be", "inundated", "by", "the", "overflow", "water", "from", "the", "Molonglo", "River", "annually", ",", "leaving", "a", "rich", "deposit", "of", "alluvium", ",", "rendering", "it", "admirably", "suited", "for", "the", "growth", "of", "lucerne", "and", "corn", "and", "comparing", "favourably", "with", "a", "great", "deal", "of", "the", "Hunter", "River", "land", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Homocysteine", "inhibits", "lysyl", "oxidase", "which", "is", "responsible", "for", "post-translational", "modifications", "of", "collagen", ",", "a", "key", "component", "to", "bone", "structure"], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "B-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Long", "term", "use", "of", "tenofovir", "disoproxil", "is", "associated", "with", "nephrotoxicity", "and", "bone", "loss", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Real", "Live", "Dress", "features", "elements", "from", "Baby", "Got", "Back", "by", "Sir", "Mix-a-Lot", "."], "label": ["B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "resulting", "flood", ",", "sent", "a", "massive", "wave", "of", "water", "and", "debris", "down", "the", "canyon", "and", "the", "Santa", "Clara", "River", "Valley", "and", "to", "the", "sea", ",", "killing", "up", "to", "600", "people", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Meyer", "is", "best", "known", "for", "his", "part", "in", "the", "periodic", "classification", "of", "the", "elements", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["CNET", "'s", "staff", "member", "was", "more", "critical", ",", "describing", "the", "game", "as", "``", "complex", "enough", "to", "keep", "you", "interested", ",", "but", "not", "quite", "good", "enough", "to", "enjoy", ".", "''"], "label": ["B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "a", "monk", "at", "Montecassino", "before", "becoming", "bishop", "at", "a", "young", "age", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lymphangioleiomyomatoses", "are", "fluid-filled", "hypodense", "structures", "present", "in", "the", "retroperitoneal", "regions", "of", "the", "abdomen", "and", "pelvis", "in", "about", "30", "%", "of", "LAM", "patients", "."], "label": ["B-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "were", "forced", "to", "carry", "the", "pregnant", "woman", "back", "up", "the", "mountain", "after", "they", "could", "not", "afford", "the", "8000", "New", "Taiwan", "dollar", "deposit", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Maharashtra", "State", "Film", "Awards", "for", "Best", "Direction", "was", "also", "presented", "to", "Patel", "."], "label": ["B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "second", "but", "eldest", "surviving", "son", ",", "the", "fifth", "Earl", ",", "was", "also", "a", "soldier", "and", "fought", "at", "the", "Battle", "of", "Waterloo", "at", "an", "early", "age", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "show", "originally", "had", "the", "working", "title", "of", "``", "Bellamy", "'s", "Kingdom", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "band", "'s", "``", "Thrown", "into", "Exile", "``", "debut", "EP", "was", "released", "on", "April", "2", ",", "2013", "via", "iTunes", ",", "and", "Amazon", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O"]}
{"text": ["St.", "Lawrence", "Avenue", "is", "the", "northernmost", "station", "on", "the", "IRT", "Pelham", "Line", "that", "does", "not", "serve", "rush-hour", "express", "service", "."], "label": ["B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Three", "years", "later", ",", "the", "name", "was", "changed", "again", "to", "Siam", "University", "to", "reflect", "the", "diversity", "in", "the", "fields", "of", "study", "offered", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "men", "'s", "10,000", "metres", "at", "the", "2018", "Commonwealth", "Games", ",", "as", "part", "of", "the", "athletics", "programme", ",", "took", "place", "in", "the", "Carrara", "Stadium", "on", "13", "April", "2018", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["HD", "10180", "h", "is", "the", "largest", "and", "outermost", "known", "planet", "in", "the", "system", "."], "label": ["B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Travancore", "Rupee", "was", "the", "highest", "denomination", "of", "currency", "issued", "for", "general", "circulation", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Class", "90s", "are", "still", "operating", "Freightliner", "services", "along", "with", "Class", "66", "and", "Class", "70", "diesels", "and", "Class", "86", "electrics", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1941", ",", "Mammoth", "Cave", "National", "Park", "was", "established", ",", "and", "the", "two", "upper", "locks", "and", "dams", "closed", "in", "1950", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "entire", "island", "of", "Guam", "was", "left", "without", "power", "after", "Paka", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "2017", ",", "Brisbane", "Airport", "handled", "over", "23", "million", "passengers", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Book", "of", "Leviticus", "prescribed", "that", "the", "Feast", "of", "Tabernacles", "should", "last", "for", "seven", "days", ",", "and", "that", "on", "the", "eighth", "day", ":"], "label": ["O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["But", "who", "knows", ",", "maybe", "something", "can", "be", "stopped", "in", "``", "The", "Grudge", "3", "``", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Work", "started", "on", "another", "totally", "new", "design", "in", "mid-1914", ",", "the", "F.E.2a", ",", "specifically", "intended", "as", "a", "``", "fighter", "''", ",", "or", "machine", "gun", "carrier", "–", "in", "the", "same", "class", "as", "the", "Vickers", "FB.5", "``", "Gunbus", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "reopened", "to", "readers", "as", "the", "Weston", "Library", "on", "21", "March", "2015", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "is", "devastated", "when", "her", "scene", "is", "cut", ",", "but", "later", "decides", "it", "is", "time", "to", "focus", "solely", "on", "acting", ";", "she", "quits", "her", "job", "at", "The", "Cheesecake", "Factory", "to", "devote", "herself", "to", "become", "an", "actress", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dudi", "Maia", "Rosa", "e", "as", "mortes", "da", "pintura", "=", "Dudi", "Maia", "Rosa", "and", "the", "deaths", "of", "painting", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "partially", "inspired", "by", "``", "Gulliver", "'s", "Travels", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "June", "15", ",", "Bloodroot", "turned", "the", "tables", "by", "winning", "the", "Prospect", "Purse", "at", "Washington", "Park", ",", "with", "Black", "Helen", "finishing", "third", "in", "her", "first", "loss", "of", "the", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Venetians", "were", "in", "a", "difficult", "situation", ":", "the", "large", "``", "taride", "``", ",", "loaded", "with", "goods", ",", "and", "with", "at", "most", "40", "armed", "soldiers", "each", ",", "were", "no", "match", "for", "the", "swift", "and", "agile", "Genoese", "galleys", ",", "each", "with", "a", "crew", "of", "about", "150", "men", "(", "rowers", "and", "50", "marines", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "the", "total", "number", "of", "PR", "seats", "was", "reduced", "from", "200", "to", "180", ",", "the", "Shikoku", "PR", "block", "shrunk", "to", "six", "seats", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "the", "sequel", "to", "the", "2004", "game", "``", "FlatOut", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "World", "War", "II", "Qantas", "modernised", "its", "fleet", "with", "Lockheed", "Constellation", "aircraft", ",", "commencing", "with", "six", "L-749", "Constellations", "from", "1947", "."], "label": ["O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1988", ",", "it", "opened", "its", "50th", "Café", "de", "Coral", "restaurant", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "University", "of", "Michigan", "Library", "holds", "the", "holograph", "of", "his", "organ", "concerto", "and", "a", "number", "of", "printed", "items", "."], "label": ["B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "result", "of", "Alekseyev", "'s", "efforts", "was", "the", "I-21", "(", "Russian", ":", "``", "istrebitel", "''", "(", "fighter", ")", ")", ",", "which", "was", "planned", "to", "be", "produced", "in", "several", "variants", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "series", "follows", "the", "events", "of", "the", "second", "Nintendo", "DS", "``", "Mega", "Man", "Star", "Force", "``", "video", "game", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "introduction", "predates", "Red", "Bull", ",", "having", "been", "first", "released", "in", "1962", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "holders", "of", "these", "accounts", "can", "withdraw", "up", "to", "US", "$", "10,000", "per", "month", "while", "travelling", "abroad", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["is", "an", "adaptation", "of", "the", "play", "Green", "Grow", "the", "Lilacs", "By", "Lynn", "Riggs", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["Two", "lengths", "are", "available", "for", "customers", ":", "Tourismo", "RH", "(", "12.14m", ")", "and", "Tourismo", "RH", "M", "(", "12.98m", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-car", "I-product-car", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-car", "I-product-car", "I-product-car", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "not", "considered", "a", "surrendering", "of", "national", "sovereignty", ",", "which", "would", "have", "implied", "the", "holding", "of", "a", "referendum", "according", "to", "article", "20", "of", "the", "constitution", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "directed", "by", "Charles", "Robert", "Carner", "and", "first", "aired", "on", "Showtime", "on", "July", "16", ",", "2000", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", ",", "Fellows", "receive", "a", "stipend", "and", "the", "opportunity", "to", "partner", "with", "several", "arts", "organizations", "for", "Fellows", "-specific", "development", "opportunities", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "thought", "that", "four", "separate", "pylons", "or", "gates", "existed", "for", "each", "of", "the", "Avatars", "of", "the", "main", "deity", "worshiped", "here", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lacking", "a", "native", "population", ",", "ownership", "of", "the", "Paracel", "Islands", "has", "been", "disputed", "since", "the", "early", "20th", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["McDonald", "'s", "restaurants", "are", "not", "present", "in", "every", "country", ",", "which", "limits", "the", "index", "'s", "usage", "."], "label": ["B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "1", "July", "1955", ",", "``", "LST-1160", "``", "was", "named", "USS", "``", "Traverse", "County", "''", "(", "LST-1160", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Boston", "Public", "Library", "possessed", "six", "paintings", "of", "a", "``", "Cross", "station", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "worked", "with", "Jim", "Belushi", "when", "the", "actor", "used", "4xy", "to", "record", "some", "demos", "and", "play", "live", "dates", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor", "I-person-actor", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "directed", "``", "The", "National", "Lampoon", "Show", "``", "(", "1975", ")", "and", "its", "road", "company", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Russians", "then", "ended", "the", "Russo-Persian", "War", "of", "1804–1813", "with", "a", "victory", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Also", ",", "to", "fill", "the", "void", "of", "his", "mother", "passing", "away", ",", "he", "had", "a", "vision", "of", "public", "service", "to", "the", "Cleveland", "Public", "Library", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "was", "the", "aunt", "of", "Lieutenant", "General", "Sir", "R", "alph", "Eastwood", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "24", "and", "25", "April", "2017", ",", "the", "31st", "Annual", "event", "raised", "$", "6,379,572", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "new", "park", "officially", "opened", "on", "May", "23", ",", "2009", ";", "however", ",", "the", "fate", "of", "Freestyle", "Music", "Park", "was", "similar", "to", "that", "of", "its", "predecessor", "and", "the", "park", "closed", "in", "September", "2009", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "such", ",", "it", "managed", "to", "carry", "on", "the", "tradition", "of", "the", "classic", "turn-based", "gameplay", "made", "popular", "by", "famous", "titles", "like", ":", "Heroes", "of", "Might", "and", "Magic", "or", "the", "series", ",", "while", "adding", "the", "online", "component", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "B-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "very", "existence", "of", "this", "award", "violates", "the", "principle", "of", "AFGNCAAP", ",", "which", "stresses", "the", "importance", "of", "leaving", "certain", "characteristics", "of", "the", "protagonist", "intentionally", "vague", "to", "allow", "the", "player", "to", "more", "easily", "envision", "themselves", "as", "the", "central", "character", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["the", "summit", "is", "in", "Yosemite", "National", "Park", "near", "the", "park", "'s", "eastern", "boundary", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2004", "she", "played", "herself", "in", "an", "episode", "of", "the", "comedy", "television", "programme", "``", "Team", "Antonsen", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Mount", "Redoubt", "is", "listed", "as", "one", "of", "the", "``", "Classic", "Eight", "Peaks", "``", "in", "the", "North", "Cascades", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Ritz", ",", "which", "has", "showering", "facilities", "and", "two", "saunas", ",", "also", "includes", "a", "stage", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "Ohio", ",", "it", "was", "the", "deadliest", "tornado", "since", "the", "Xenia", "F5", "during", "the", "Super", "Outbreak", "of", "April", "3", ",", "1974", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Galaxy", "Game", "is", "a", "space", "combat", "arcade", "game", "developed", "in", "1971", "during", "the", "early", "era", "of", "video", "games", "."], "label": ["B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Typhoon", "Durian", "killed", "85", "in", "the", "country", "and", "injured", "1,379", "others", "."], "label": ["B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "east", "ridge", "leads", "off", "to", "the", "summit", "of", "Foel", "Hafod-fynydd", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "this", "book", "they", "assumed", "that", "the", "left-wing", "rioters", "of", "May", "68", "were", "totalitarian", "stalinists", ",", "and", "psychoanalyzed", "them", "saying", "that", "they", "were", "affected", "by", "a", "sordid", "infantilism", "caught", "up", "in", "an", "Oedipal", "revolt", "against", "the", "Father", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "eventually", "worked", "for", "the", "company", "that", "had", "produced", "the", "special", "paper", "for", "the", "Operation", "Bernhard", "forgeries", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "show", "presents", "a", "school", "uprising", "similar", "to", "the", "Soweto", "uprising", "on", "16", "June", "1976", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Before", "that", ",", "the", "residents", "survived", "by", "fishing", ",", "limited", "trading", ",", "and", "salvage", "of", "ships", "wrecked", "on", "Elbow", "Reef", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "launch", "of", "Astra", "1D", "allowed", "Sky", "to", "expand", "the", "multichannels", "package", "further", ",", "including", "the", "launch", "of", "Sky", "'s", "pay-per-view", "Box", "Office", "channels", "in", "January", "1997", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Believing", "the", "odds", "hopeless", ",", "Lieutenant", "Audie", "Murphy", "ordered", "his", "men", "to", "withdraw", "into", "the", "woods", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "destroyed", "in", "the", "1755", "Lisbon", "earthquake", "and", "fragments", "of", "it", "are", "housed", "in", "the", "church", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Initially", ",", "it", "was", "suspected", "that", "the", "accident", "was", "due", "to", "the", "effect", "of", "Xangsane", ",", "but", "it", "was", "later", "discovered", "that", "the", "accident", "was", "due", "to", "a", "pilot", "error", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Renovations", "and", "the", "Hyatt", "Regency", "Crystal", "City", "layout", "caused", "problems", "during", "the", "2008", "convention", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2007", ",", "the", "team", "moved", "to", "the", "Galen", "Center", "as", "its", "home", "court", ",", "but", "uses", "the", "old", "venues", "if", "the", "Galen", "Center", "is", "reserved", "for", "other", "events", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "reform", ",", "in", "turn", ",", "was", "facilitated", "by", "the", "Pugachev", "'s", "Rebellion", "of", "1774–1775", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "accidental", "discovery", "of", "her", "intact", "tomb", "during", "the", "Hungarian", "Revolution", "of", "1848", "has", "provided", "an", "opportunity", "for", "patriotic", "demonstrations", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Morrison", "'s", "Cafeterias", "were", "founded", "and", "operated", "as", "a", "racially-segregated", "private", "business", "."], "label": ["B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Cheddar", "'s", "Scratch", "Kitchen", "serves", "a", "variety", "of", "made-from-scratch", "dishes", "."], "label": ["B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "stands", "behind", "the", "goal", "areas", "were", "``", "Eski", "Açık", "``", "with", "a", "seating", "capacity", "of", "7,962", ",", "and", "``", "Yeni", "Açık", "``", "with", "a", "seating", "capacity", "of", "13,065", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "La", "Vicaría", "``", "exemplifies", "genre", "painting", "of", "the", "19th", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "unusual", "for", "a", "``", "menologion", "``", "from", "that", "era", "to", "be", "so", "richly", "painted", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
