{"text": ["Another", "draw", "to", "the", "mountainous", "Gunma", "is", "the", "ski", "resorts", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "old", "alignment", "of", "Riverside", "Drive", "in", "Riverview", "continued", "to", "be", "known", "as", "Riverside", "Drive", ",", "serving", "a", "number", "of", "apartment", "building", "complexes", ",", "and", "has", "a", "cul-de-sac", "at", "each", "end", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "prompt", "resignation", "from", "the", "UCRI", "and", "annulment", "of", "the", "March", "18", "mid-term", "elections", "did", "not", "immediately", "dispel", "the", "threat", "of", "a", "coup", "attempt", ",", "however", ",", "and", "mutinies", "in", "April", "and", "August", "resulted", "in", "the", "appointment", "of", "Army", "General", "Juan", "Carlos", "Onganía", "(", "who", "successfully", "rebelled", "against", "his", "``", "Red", "''", "superiors", ")", "as", "Head", "of", "the", "Military", "Joint", "Chiefs", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "he", "was", "18", ",", "Maynard", "was", "accepted", "at", "the", "College", "Conservatory", "of", "Music", "at", "the", "University", "of", "Cincinnati", "where", ",", "among", "other", "productions", ",", "he", "starred", "as", "Otto", "Kringelein", "in", "``", "Grand", "Hotel", "``", ",", "and", "had", "a", "lead", "role", "in", "``", "Godspell", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2005", ",", "the", "Center", "for", "the", "Study", "of", "Confucian", "Religion", "was", "established", "and", "``", "guoxue", "''", "(", "``", "national", "learning", "''", ")", "started", "to", "be", "implemented", "in", "public", "schools", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kerkorian", "now", "distanced", "himself", "from", "the", "operations", "of", "the", "studio", ",", "focusing", "on", "MGM", "Grand", "Hotel", "by", "investing", "$", "120", "million", "."], "label": ["B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O"]}
{"text": ["Since", "ancient", "times", ",", "it", "has", "been", "especially", "revered", ",", "ranking", "with", "the", "Grand", "Shrine", "of", "Ise", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Looking", "to", "improve", "the", "team", ",", "Sutter", "completed", "two", "significant", "deals", "at", "the", "March", "4", "trade", "deadline", ",", "acquiring", "defenceman", "Jordan", "Leopold", "from", "the", "Colorado", "Avalanche", "and", "centre", "Olli", "Jokinen", "from", "the", "Phoenix", "Coyotes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O"]}
{"text": ["Eberstadt", "died", "as", "a", "result", "of", "cardiac", "problems", "at", "the", "Walter", "Reed", "Army", "Medical", "Center", "in", "Washington", ",", "D.C", ".", "in", "1969", "."], "label": ["B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Both", "parts", "were", "glossed", "by", "The", "Tremulous", "Hand", "of", "Worcester", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O"]}
{"text": ["Given", "the", "increasing", "number", "of", "passengers", "travelling", "through", "the", "airport", "due", "to", "connections", "provided", "by", "Air", "Iceland", ",", "both", "domestic", "to", "Nerlerit", "Inaat", "Airport", "and", "international", "to", "Iceland", ",", "the", "number", "of", "fixed-schedule", "helicopter", "flights", "to", "Tasiilaq", "is", "not", "sufficient", "to", "cover", "demand", ",", "due", "to", "a", "single", "Bell", "212", "helicopter", "of", "Air", "Greenland", "stationed", "at", "the", "airport", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2002", ",", "he", "was", "presented", "with", "the", "Medal", "of", "the", "Garden", "Club", "of", "New", "Jersey", "(", "GCNJ", ")", ",", "the", "organization", "'s", "highest", "honor", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "flag", "is", "a", "green", ",", "red", "and", "yellow", "tricolour", "adapted", "from", "the", "coat", "of", "arms", "of", "Carlow", "town", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "followed", "by", "an", "updated", "arcade", "version", "titled", "Street", "Fighter", "EX", "Plus", ",", "as", "well", "as", "a", "PlayStation-exclusive", "home", "console", "version", "titled", "Street", "Fighter", "EX", "Plus", "α", ",", "both", "released", "in", "1997", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "rest", "fell", "to", "defending", "Mitsubishi", "A6M", "Zeros", "and", "anti-aircraft", "fire", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "Kennedy", "'s", "assassination", ",", "vice", "president", "Lyndon", "Baines", "Johnson", "served", "out", "the", "remainder", "of", "the", "term", ",", "using", "appeals", "to", "finish", "the", "job", "that", "Kennedy", "had", "started", "to", "pass", "a", "remarkable", "package", "of", "liberal", "legislation", "that", "he", "called", "the", "Great", "Society", "."], "label": ["O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Born", "the", "eldest", "son", "of", "Lieutenant-Colonel", "John", "Luard", "and", "educated", "at", "the", "Royal", "Military", "Academy", "Sandhurst", ",", "Luard", "was", "commissioned", "into", "the", "51st", "Regiment", "of", "Foot", "in", "1845", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Government", "Accountability", "Project", "and", "the", "ACLU", "helped", "defend", "van", "Buren", ",", "and", "the", "State", "Department", "eventually", "allowed", "him", "to", "retire", "with", "his", "standard", "pension", "and", "benefits", "."], "label": ["B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "school", "has", "graduated", "five", "Fortune", "500", "Chief", "Executives", "(", "the", "most", "of", "any", "school", "according", "to", "Business", "Insider", ")", ",", "justices", "of", "the", "Texas", "Supreme", "Court", ",", "federal", "and", "state", "judges", ",", "and", "several", "U.S", ".", "and", "state", "government", "officials", ",", "senators", ",", "and", "representatives", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["By", "July", "2008", "the", "Obama", "campaign", "had", "some", "300", "persons", "working", "on", "foreign", "policy", ",", "and", "organized", "along", "bureaucratic", "lines", "like", "a", "``", "miniature", "State", "Department", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "week", "17", ",", "Carolina", "'s", "38-10", "victory", "gave", "them", "a", "franchise-best", "15-1", "regular", "season", "record", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "former", "Netherlands", "Antilles", "the", "rijksdaalder", "circulated", "until", "2011", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["CBC", "began", "delivering", "news", "online", "in", "1996", "via", "the", "Newsworld", "Online", "website", "."], "label": ["B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Seven", "new", "characters", "are", "introduced", "in", "Tekken", "6", ",", "but", "two", "are", "not", "playable", "bosses", ",", "and", "in", "``", "Bloodline", "Rebellion", "``", "and", "the", "console", "version", "two", "additional", "characters", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", ",", "the", "Umayyad", "authorities", "were", "preoccupied", "by", "the", "rebellion", "of", "al-Harith", "ibn", "Surayj", "in", "Khurasan", "itself", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "I-person-other", "I-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Two", "star", "systems", "with", "known", "exoplanets", ",", "HD", "93083", "and", "WASP-66", ",", "lie", "within", "Antlia", ",", "as", "do", "NGC", "2997", ",", "a", "spiral", "galaxy", ",", "and", "the", "Antlia", "Dwarf", "Galaxy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "he", "first", "started", "attending", "Long", "Beach", "State", "University", ",", "he", "majored", "in", "kinesiology", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Along", "with", "other", "misfortunes", "in", "the", "1920s", ",", "foot-and-mouth", "disease", "struck", "in", "1926", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "budget", "for", "the", "film", "was", "around", "AUD", "$", "3m", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Ioannis", "Kasoulides", "served", "the", "Democratic", "Rally", "in", "various", "roles", ",", "including", "that", "of", "Chair", "of", "the", "party", "'s", "Youth", "Organization", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dance", "music", "fans", "and", "DJ", "'s", "quickly", "appreciated", "Rucker", "'s", "vocals", "and", "rhythm", ",", "which", "was", "described", "as", "``", "mystical", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "more", "than", "a", "year", "the", "monthly", "fee", "was", "2,995", "DKK", "(", ")", "per", "month", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["So", "all", "power", "stations", "under", "CLP", "Power", "burn", "ULSD", "instead", "of", "higher", "sulfur", "alternatives", "now", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Union", "of", "Czechoslovak", "Mathematicians", "and", "Physicists", "in", "1959", "awarded", "him", "the", "title", "of", "``", "honorary", "member", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "supported", "the", "Patriot", "cause", "in", "the", "American", "Revolution", ",", "participating", "in", "the", "Wyoming", "Valley", "Massacre", "on", "the", "Patriot", "side", ",", "as", "well", "as", "the", "Battle", "of", "Newtown", "in", "1779", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bottom", "metals", "which", "accept", "detachable", "magazines", "are", "called", "``", "detachable", "bottom", "metals", "``", "(", "DBM", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sunderland", "Reserves", "played", "a", "single", "season", "in", "the", "Wearside", "Football", "League", "in", "1979–80", ",", "before", "joining", "The", "Central", "League", "in", "1983", "."], "label": ["B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Moved", "to", "White", "House", ",", "then", "to", "Cold", "Harbor", "May", "27–31", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "2019–20", "Denver", "Pioneers", "men", "'s", "basketball", "team", "represented", "the", "University", "of", "Denver", "in", "the", "2019–20", "NCAA", "Division", "I", "men", "'s", "basketball", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Minneapolis", "Public", "Library", "'s", "first", "building", "was", "the", "Main", "Library", ",", "opened", "in", "1889", "."], "label": ["B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["According", "to", "a", "Rede", "Record", "documentary", "about", "the", "imprisonment", "of", "Edir", "Macedo", "(", "UCKG", "founder", "and", "Record", "owner", ")", ",", "some", "lines", "of", "the", "character", "were", "based", "on", "public", "speeches", "by", "him", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2018", ",", "Cocke", "created", "the", "theme", "used", "in", "the", "Tom", "Clancy", "'s", "Rainbow", "Six", "Siege", "invitational", "Esports", "competition", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "the", "section", "Rottweil-Tuttlingen", ",", "the", "Ringzug", "of", "the", "Hohenzollerische", "Landesbahn", "provides", "local", "service", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Despite", "a", "27", "mbar", "increase", "in", "pressure", "in", "12", "hours", ",", "convective", "activity", "increased", "prior", "to", "Kenna", "making", "landfall", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Federal", "Data", "Services", "Hub", "is", "a", "tool", "used", "to", "facilitate", "the", "government-backed", "Patient", "Protection", "and", "Affordable", "Care", "Act", "health", "coverage", "program", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Throughout", "her", "career", ",", "she", "has", "done", "segments", "for", "the", "TV", "Guide", "Channel", "'s", "coverage", "of", "the", "Golden", "Globes", ",", "the", "Catherine", "Zeta-Jones", "benefit", "for", "the", "Motion", "Picture", "and", "Television", "Fund", ",", "and", "the", "E", "!"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "B-person-actor", "I-person-actor", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "ancient", "written", "Chinese", ",", "the", "character", "for", "chopsticks", "was", "``", "zhu", "''", "(", "箸", ";", "Middle", "Chinese", "reconstruction", ":", "d̪jwo-", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "became", "an", "associate", "of", "the", "National", "Academy", "of", "Design", "in", "1859", ",", "and", "was", "elevated", "to", "full", "membership", "two", "years", "later", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Moreover", ",", "the", "mutant", "p53", "protein", "itself", "can", "inhibit", "normal", "p53", "protein", "levels", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "explains", "why", "ferritin", "levels", "remain", "relative", "low", "in", "Hereditary", "hemochromatosis", ",", "while", "transferrin", "saturation", "is", "high", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Limermont", "was", "promoted", "to", "Ensign", "in", "1748", ",", "and", "to", "Lieutenant", "in", "1756", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Several", "other", "churches", ",", "roughly", "15", "holiness", "denominations", "that", "had", "also", "split", "from", "the", "Methodist", "Episcopal", "Church", ",", "joined", "the", "Church", "of", "the", "Nazarene", "in", "1907", "and", "1908", ",", "and", "it", "became", "international", "soon", "thereafter", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2003", "the", "band", "was", "nominated", "for", "the", "TMF", "Awards", "and", "an", "Edison", "Award", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O"]}
{"text": ["Hopper", "went", "on", "to", "direct", "feature", "films", ",", "such", "as", ",", "``", "The", "Atomic", "City", "``", "(", "1952", ")", ",", "``", "Pony", "Express", "``", "(", "1953", ")", ",", "``", "Secret", "of", "the", "Incas", "``", "(", "1954", ")", ",", "and", "``", "The", "Private", "War", "of", "Major", "Benson", "``", "(", "1955", ")", ",", "the", "latter", "three", "with", "actor", "Charlton", "Heston", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor", "I-person-actor", "O"]}
{"text": ["Peking", "duck", "is", "originally", "roasted", "in", "a", "closed", "oven", "(", ")", ",", "and", "Bianyifang", "is", "the", "restaurant", "that", "keeps", "this", "tradition", "."], "label": ["B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "release", "came", "not", "too", "long", "before", "the", "start", "of", "his", "new", "show", "at", "the", "Paris", "Las", "Vegas", "hotel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O"]}
{"text": ["Besides", "his", "full-time", "job", "in", "the", "military", ",", "Kroon", "often", "helps", "her", "with", "her", "work", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2001", ",", "they", "created", "a", "new", "company", ",", "TK", "&", "amp", ";", "C", "'s", "LLC", ",", "to", "administer", "licensing", "rights", "for", "the", "brand", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "nickname", "was", "invented", "by", "Alexandre", "Dumas", "père", "who", "titled", "his", "first", "novel", "on", "the", "Trilogy", "of", "Valois", ":", "``", "La", "Reine", "Margot", "``", "(", "1845", ")", ",", "describing", "in", "the", "novel", "the", "St.", "Bartholomew", "'s", "Day", "massacre", "and", "the", "intrigues", "of", "subsequent", "courtiers", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "name", "Rhizaria", "for", "the", "expanded", "group", "was", "introduced", "by", "Cavalier-Smith", "in", "2002", ",", "who", "also", "included", "the", "centrohelids", "and", "Apusozoa", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-livingthing", "O", "B-other-livingthing", "O"]}
{"text": ["Chemotherapy", "(", "drug", "treatment", "for", "cancer", ")", "may", "be", "used", "before", "surgery", ",", "after", "surgery", ",", "or", "instead", "of", "surgery", "for", "those", "cases", "in", "which", "surgery", "is", "considered", "unsuitable", "."], "label": ["B-other-medical", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Criminal", "Justice", "and", "Immigration", "Act", "2008", "amended", "Part", "3A", "of", "the", "Public", "Order", "Act", "1986", "to", "extend", "hate", "crime", "legislation", "to", "cover", "``", "hatred", "against", "a", "group", "of", "persons", "defined", "by", "reference", "to", "sexual", "orientation", "(", "whether", "towards", "persons", "of", "the", "same", "sex", ",", "the", "opposite", "sex", "or", "both", ")", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "released", "under", "the", "terms", "of", "the", "GNU", "General", "Public", "License", "(", "GPL", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "I-product-software", "I-product-software", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Isavuconazonium", "comprises", "an", "``", "N", "''", "-", "(", "3-acetoxypropyl", ")", "-", "''", "N", "''", "-methylamino-carboxymethyl", "group", "linked", "through", "an", "ester", "moiety", "to", "the", "triazole", "nitrogen", "in", "isavuconazole", "."], "label": ["B-other-medical", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O"]}
{"text": ["R.", "C.", "Majumdar", "and", "D.", "D.", "Kosambi", "note", "that", "Seleucus", "appeared", "to", "have", "fared", "poorly", "after", "ceding", "large", "territories", "west", "of", "the", "Indus", "to", "Chandragupta", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "doing", "so", ",", "it", "became", "the", "last", "of", "the", "12", "VFL", "teams", "to", "win", "a", "flag", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "yard", "currently", "offers", "refurbishment", "and", "parts", "support", "for", "Contessa", "yachts", ",", "as", "well", "as", "refitting", "of", "other", "yacht", "makes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Prostitutes", "frequent", "bars", ",", "casinos", "and", "nightclubs", ";", "some", "are", "addicted", "to", "heroin", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O"]}
{"text": ["Mineral", "Wells", "is", "located", "at", "(", "32.808594", ",", "-98.101859", ")", "."], "label": ["B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "same", "building", "with", "the", "museum", "is", "also", "Ace", "Cafe", "Lahti", "restaurant", ",", "popular", "destination", "among", "motorcyclists", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Geologically", "the", "Kaiserstuhl", "can", "be", "divided", "into", "two", "parts", ":", "the", "sedimentary", "and", "volcanic", "part", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "line", "was", "doubled", "in", "1874", "when", "the", "Clifton", "Extension", "Railway", "opened", ",", "then", "expanded", "to", "four", "tracks", "and", "platforms", "in", "1888", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Eastern", "Catholic", "Churches", "'", "Holy", "Week", "observances", "and", "customs", "are", "generally", "the", "same", "as", "in", "the", "rites", "of", "the", "corresponding", "Eastern", "Orthodox", "or", "Oriental", "Orthodox", "Church", "or", "Assyrian", "Church", "of", "the", "East", "."], "label": ["B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O"]}
{"text": ["Other", "garden", "plays", "have", "included", "The", "Tempest", "on", "the", "lake", ",", "directed", "by", "Nevill", "Coghill", "in", "1949", ",", "and", "Twelfth", "Night", "in", "the", "Provost", "'s", "garden", ",", "directed", "by", "Provost", "Jonathan", "Bate", "and", "undergraduate", "Georgia", "Figgis", "in", "2016", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Separation", "of", "graphite", "oxide", "layers", "is", "proportional", "to", "the", "size", "of", "alcohol", "molecule", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Flickr", "has", "over", "40", "million", "geotagged", "photos", "uploaded", "by", "400", "thousand", "users", ",", "and", "still", "growing", "at", "a", "rapid", "pace", "."], "label": ["B-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "LDW", "system", ",", "which", "utilize", "a", "small", "camera", ",", "speed", "sensor", ",", "an", "indicator", "and", "an", "audible", "warning", "buzzer", ",", "was", "offered", "on", "models", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "brigade", "was", "involved", "in", "heavy", "fighting", "at", "the", "Battle", "of", "Port", "Gibson", "on", "May", "1", ",", "1863", ",", "losing", "222", "casualties", ",", "and", "the", "Battle", "of", "Champion", "'s", "Hill", "on", "16", "May", ",", "losing", "268", "casualties", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Her", "papers", "are", "part", "of", "the", "Human", "Sexuality", "Collection", "at", "Cornell", "University", "Library", "along", "with", "the", "archives", "of", "On", "Our", "Backs", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "makes", "similar", "revisions", "to", "the", "Controlled", "Substance", "Import", "and", "Export", "Act", "at", "21", "U.S.C", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "end", "of", "2006", ",", "Bogue", "joined", "the", "TV", "show", "``", "Guau", "!"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "origins", "of", "the", "A-League", "go", "back", "to", "1986", "and", "1987", "with", "the", "creation", "of", "three", "unrelated", "semi-professional", "soccer", "leagues", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "campus", "includes", "three", "facilities", ":", "the", "Wilzig", "Hospital", ",", "the", "Provident", "Bank", "Ambulatory", "Center", ",", "and", "the", "Christie", "Kerr", "Women", "'s", "Health", "Center", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Fo", "''", "is", "the", "Chinese", "word", "for", "``", "Buddha", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "the", "17th", "edition", "of", "the", "Challenge", "Bell", ",", "and", "was", "part", "of", "the", "WTA", "International", "tournaments", "of", "the", "2009", "WTA", "Tour", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1866", "Edward", "Drinker", "Cope", "chose", "three", "nonserrated", "teeth", "from", "the", "original", "syntype", "series", "of", "fourteen", "as", "the", "lectotypes", "of", "``", "Deinodon", "horridus", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Additions", "were", "made", "in", "1961", ",", "1966", ",", "and", "1973", "by", "Fritiof", "Fryxell", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "thus", "related", "to", "the", "Welsh", "Gofannon", "and", "the", "Gaulish", "Gobannus", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "1935", ",", "a", "second", "machine", "was", "ordered", ",", "designated", "the", "``", "Type", "138B", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "sold", "at", "auction", "in", "2009", "for", "US", "$", "324,500", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Frédéric", "de", "Lafresnaye", "placed", "it", "in", "its", "own", "monotypic", "genus", "``", "Acanthisitta", "``", "in", "1842", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "prototype", "Żak-1", "was", "first", "flown", "on", "March", "23", ",", "1947", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Euro", "Dance", "Festival", ",", "located", "annually", "at", "Europa-Park", "since", "2007", ",", "is", "best", "known", "for", "its", "wide", "range", "of", "music", "and", "dancing", "styles", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Hearing", "that", "Edgar", "Selwyn", "was", "casting", "his", "play", "``", "The", "Country", "Boy", "``", "for", "a", "road", "tour", ",", "she", "went", "to", "his", "office", "and", "talked", "him", "into", "letting", "her", "audition", "for", "the", "lead", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "new", "Lotus", "Elan", "was", "announced", "at", "the", "2010", "Paris", "Motor", "Show", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-product-car", "I-product-car", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Both", "classes", "are", "now", "sometimes", "referred", "to", "as", "``", "Networker", "Turbos", "``", ",", "a", "name", "which", "was", "derived", "some", "three", "years", "later", "for", "the", "project", "that", "resulted", "in", "the", "visually", "similar", "and", "EMUs", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Cristobal", "Colon", "``", ",", "along", "with", "her", "sister", "ship", ",", "``", "Juan", "Alejandro", "Acosta", "``", ",", "were", "driven", "ashore", "and", "wrecked", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "only", "changed", "after", "the", "new", "Neubaulokomotive", "DR", "Class", "99.77-79", "was", "put", "into", "service", "in", "1953", ",", "and", "the", "transport", "volume", "reached", "the", "1930s", "levels", "again", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Psychedelic", "Desert", "'s", "music", "ranges", "from", "ambient", "drone", "soundscapes", "to", "layers", "of", "fluctuating", "sounds", "which", "stimulate", "the", "brainwaves", "of", "the", "listener", "."], "label": ["B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Racine", "Nunatak", "is", "a", "nunatak", ",", "960", "m", ",", "located", "3", "nautical", "miles", "(", "6", "km", ")", "west", "of", "the", "lower", "part", "of", "Reedy", "Glacier", "and", "7", "nautical", "miles", "(", "13", "km", ")", "east-southeast", "of", "Berry", "Peaks", "."], "label": ["B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "all", "speak", "only", "in", "Lingala", "with", "anyone", "on", "their", "way", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["From", "the", "picnic", "area", ",", "a", "walking", "track", "makes", "its", "way", "approximately", "to", "the", "top", "of", "Mount", "Banks", ",", "where", "there", "is", "a", "trigonometric", "station", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Varaha", "slew", "the", "demon", "and", "retrieved", "the", "Earth", "from", "the", "ocean", ",", "lifting", "it", "on", "his", "tusks", ",", "and", "restored", "Bhudevi", "to", "her", "place", "in", "the", "universe", "."], "label": ["B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "rest", "of", "the", "Act", "was", "brought", "into", "force", "on", "1", "February", "2004", "by", "article", "2", "of", "the", "Legal", "Deposit", "Libraries", "Act", "2003", "(", "Commencement", ")", "Order", "2004", "(", "SI", "2004/130", ")", "(", "C", "5", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "comprises", "three", "species", "that", "are", "found", "in", "the", "Southern", "Alps", "of", "the", "South", "Island", "of", "New", "Zealand", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "I-location-island", "I-location-island", "I-location-island", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "longest", "ship", "to", "have", "ever", "navigated", "through", "the", "narrows", "past", "Suomenlinna", "sea", "fortress", "was", "MS", "``", "Oriana", "''", "(", "260", "m", ")", ",", "but", "that", "was", "only", "possible", "due", "to", "extremely", "good", "weather", "conditions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "time", ",", "it", "was", "planned", "that", "the", "ESPN", "Zone", "restaurant", "would", "increase", "promotional", "efforts", "with", "the", "two", "sports", "teams", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", "to", "careful", "screening", "of", "donors", ",", "each", "batch", "of", "milk", "is", "tested", "for", "bacterial", "counts", "before", "pasteurization", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "annual", "Kidquake", "events", "bring", "over", "800", "K-5", "students", "from", "34", "classes", "to", "the", "San", "Francisco", "Public", "Library", "for", "two", "days", "of", "assemblies", "and", "intimate", "workshops", "with", "acclaimed", "children", "’", "s", "authors", ",", "and", "hundreds", "of", "free", "books", "and", "giveaways", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "Sanskrit", "the", "Hindu", "origin", "term", "``", "deva-raja", "``", "could", "have", "different", "meanings", "such", "as", "``", "god-king", "''", "or", "``", "king", "of", "the", "gods", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "Nara", "International", "Film", "Festival", "was", "held", "in", "2010", "with", "the", "financial", "support", "of", "mainly", "local", "companies", ",", "government", "subsidies", ",", "and", "contributions", "from", "individuals", "who", "donated", "¥10,000", "for", "a", "NIFF", "membership", "."], "label": ["B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "GWR", "7400", "Class", "were", "very", "similar", "to", "the", "6400", "Class", ",", "but", "were", "not", "auto-fitted", "and", "had", "a", "higher", "boiler", "pressure", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "autumn", "of", "2004", "arrives", "on", "the", "national", "circuit", "with", "7", "Gold", "and", "the", "program", "``", "Aria", "Pulita", "``", ",", "where", "he", "manages", "to", "put", "together", "a", "real", "popular", "uprising", "to", "block", "a", "bipartisan", "proposal", "for", "the", "extension", "of", "electoral", "reimbursements", "also", "to", "elections", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Moses", "Mabhida", "Stadium", "was", "completed", "in", "2009", "and", "involved", "massive", "regeneration", "of", "the", "surrounding", "infrastructure", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "example", ",", "the", "behavior", "of", "underground", "walls", "has", "been", "evaluated", "for", "the", "Northridge", "earthquake", "using", "numerical", "methods", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "he", "was", "about", "forty", ",", "the", "Yuan-Chao", "Rebellion", "broken", "broke", "out", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "first", "appears", "in", "Episode", "62", "-", "``", "The", "Lost", "City", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "first", "play", ",", "``", "The", "Hamlet", "of", "Stepney", "Green", "``", ",", "was", "produced", "at", "the", "Oxford", "Playhouse", "in", "1957", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["According", "to", "Barrier", ",", "Brown", "was", "``", "no", "artist", "''", "and", "had", "no", "previous", "experience", "directing", "or", "animating", "films", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Typhoon", "Durian", "killed", "85", "in", "the", "country", "and", "injured", "1,379", "others", "."], "label": ["B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Scientologists", "warn", "that", "reading", "the", "Xenu", "story", "without", "proper", "authorization", "could", "cause", "pneumonia", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "ships", "were", "equipped", "with", "a", "torpedo-carrying", "DASH", "drone", "helicopter", ";", "its", "telescoping", "hangar", "and", "landing", "pad", "were", "positioned", "amidships", "aft", "of", "the", "mack", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lord", "Howe", "Island", "Marine", "Park", "was", "declared", "after", "it", "was", "recognised", "as", "an", "area", "with", "outstanding", "natural", "values", ",", "an", "extraordinary", "array", "of", "marine", "habitats", "and", "biodiversity", ",", "rich", "maritime", "cultural", "heritage", "and", "social", "and", "economic", "importance", "to", "the", "island", "community", ",", "giving", "it", "both", "national", "and", "international", "importance", "."], "label": ["B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "this", "mall", "(", "1977", ")", ",", "and", "the", "former", "Lansdowne", "Park", "racetrack", "(", "1924–1960", ")", "have", "retained", "their", "separate", "identity", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Another", "seasoning", "was", "vinegar", ",", "which", "was", "produced", "by", "extra", "fermentation", "of", "new", "wine", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "later", "a", "technical", "assessor", "for", "the", "Inquiry", "into", "the", "Piper", "Alpha", "disaster", ",", "1988", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["From", "September", "1", ",", "1970", "he", "joined", "the", "Vienna", "Volksoper", "and", "on", "1", "March", "1973", "he", "finally", "became", "a", "member", "of", "the", "Vienna", "Philharmonic", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "was", "followed", "in", "September", "2007", "by", "the", "Sadrist", "Movement", ",", "who", "complained", "the", "Alliance", "was", "``", "dominated", "by", "some", "parties", "''", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "discovered", "and", "named", "by", "Discovery", "Investigations", "personnel", "on", "the", "``", "William", "Scoresby", "``", "in", "February", "1936", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "museum", "opened", "in", "1997", "and", "is", "in", "a", "building", "that", "also", "houses", "the", "Negro", "Leagues", "Baseball", "Museum", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O"]}
{"text": ["Afterwards", ",", "the", "eastern", "and", "southern", "stands", "of", "Estadio", "Lolo", "Fernández", "were", "removed", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Though", "The", "Dillards", "were", "already", "an", "established", "bluegrass", "band", ",", "their", "biggest", "claim", "to", "fame", "is", "performing", "musically", "as", "members", "of", "the", "fictional", "Darling", "family", "on", "``", "The", "Andy", "Griffith", "Show", "``", ",", "introducing", "bluegrass", "to", "many", "Americans", "who", "had", "never", "heard", "it", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "trained", "and", "played", "home", "games", "at", "Clearwater", "Athletic", "Field", "from", "1947", "to", "1954", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kuching", "International", "Airport", "(", "KCH", ")", "(", "ICAO", "Code", ":", "WBGG", ")", "is", "the", "main", "gateway", "for", "air", "passengers", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "B-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", ",", "several", "power", "lines", "were", "down", "at", "the", "Bullhead", "City", "Airport", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "June", "1992", ",", "the", "ceremonial", "first", "pitch", "was", "thrown", "at", "the", "site", "of", "the", "new", "Jacobs", "Field", "before", "construction", "of", "the", "building", "began", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "bronzed", "bust", "of", "Lord", "sits", "outside", "the", "mall", ",", "near", "the", "California", "Pizza", "Kitchen", "entrance", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "march", "ended", "back", "in", "the", "park", "where", "they", "officially", "changed", "the", "name", "from", "McAlester", "Park", "to", "Peace", "Park", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O"]}
{"text": ["Piton", "de", "la", "Fournaise", "is", "one", "of", "the", "most", "active", "volcanoes", "in", "the", "world", ",", "with", "more", "than", "150", "recorded", "eruptions", "since", "the", "17th", "century", "."], "label": ["B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Finally", ",", "in", "1967", ",", "the", "theatre", "was", "named", "the", "Gem", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "those", "events", "a", "museum", "dedicated", "to", "the", "Orange", "Revolution", "(", "``", "Pomarancheva", "Revolyuziya", "''", "-ukr", ".", ")"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["One", "big", "event", "that", "made", "the", "criticism", "even", "stronger", "was", "Hurricane", "David", "that", "hit", "in", "1979", ",", "which", "slowed", "the", "economy", "even", "more", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "accidental", "discovery", "of", "her", "intact", "tomb", "during", "the", "Hungarian", "Revolution", "of", "1848", "has", "provided", "an", "opportunity", "for", "patriotic", "demonstrations", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Later", "construction", "added", "324", "units", "(", "492", "guest", "rooms", ")", "in", "a", "new", "building", ",", "Kidani", "Village", ",", "which", "opened", "in", "phases", "and", "was", "completed", "in", "2009", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "La", "Vicaría", "``", "exemplifies", "genre", "painting", "of", "the", "19th", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dudi", "Maia", "Rosa", "e", "as", "mortes", "da", "pintura", "=", "Dudi", "Maia", "Rosa", "and", "the", "deaths", "of", "painting", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "final", "1960s", "issue", ",", "``", "Amazing", "Fantasy", "``", "#", "15", "(", "cover-dated", "Aug.", "1962", ")", ",", "introduced", "the", "popular", "superhero", "character", "Spider-Man", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "unusual", "for", "a", "``", "menologion", "``", "from", "that", "era", "to", "be", "so", "richly", "painted", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
