{"text": ["The", "stream", "flows", "to", "the", "northwest", "passing", "under", "U.S.", "Route", "160", "and", "enters", "Dry", "Creek", "about", "one-half", "mile", "northeast", "of", "Royal", "Oak", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater", "I-location-bodiesofwater", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["While", "in", "the", "Hopper", "company", ",", "she", "realized", "that", "chorus", "and", "understudy", "jobs", "were", "not", "acting", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Private", "Harris", "Hawthorn", "of", "the", "121st", "New", "York", "claimed", "his", "capture", "and", "applied", "for", "and", "received", "the", "Medal", "of", "Honor", "for", "this", "act", "in", "the", "year", "1894", "."], "label": ["O", "B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "I-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "monument", "was", "sculptured", "by", "Felix", "de", "Weldon", "from", "the", "image", "of", "the", "second", "flag", "raising", "on", "Mount", "Suribachi", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O"]}
{"text": ["Some", "key", "details", "of", "Hermann", "de", "Tournai", "'s", "account", "are", "confirmed", "by", "the", "Christchurch", "Priory", "cartulary", ",", "the", "bulk", "of", "which", "was", "compiled", "by", "1372", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "I-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "axe", "was", "delivered", "to", "the", "Cultural", "Department", "of", "the", "Rana", "Museum", "on", "1", "July", "2004", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "displacement", "of", "the", "Russian", "-speaking", "population", "from", "the", "industrial", "sphere", ",", "science", "and", "education", "has", "weakened", "those", "spheres", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "previously", "worked", "as", "an", "analyst", "for", "the", "Arizona", "Diamondbacks", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O"]}
{"text": ["Two", "years", "later", ",", "in", "November", "2006", ",", "after", "another", "major", "personnel", "change", ",", "Summer", "Hymns", "released", "Backward", "Masks", ",", "again", "on", "Misra", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "young", "director", "succumbed", "to", "Spanish", "Influenza", "and", "died", "later", "that", "year", ";", "October", "23", ",", "1918", ",", "at", "the", "age", "of", "28", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "defeated", "Cynthia", "Steel", "in", "the", "2004", "election", "46.12", "%", "to", "33.53", "%", ",", "and", "was", "unopposed", "in", "his", "2010", "re-election", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["21", "on", "the", "Singles", "Chart", "and", "was", "used", "in", "the", "Vancouver", "2010", "Winter", "Olympics", "``", "With", "Glowing", "Hearts/Des", "Plus", "Brillants", "Exploits", "``", "advertisement", "campaign", "and", "in", "pre-event", "intros", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Following", "the", "introduction", "of", "the", "Local", "Governance", "(", "Scotland", ")", "Act", "2004", "local", "elections", "are", "held", "using", "the", "single", "transferable", "vote", ",", "with", "this", "taking", "place", "for", "the", "first", "time", "in", "2007", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "University", "of", "Michigan", "Library", "holds", "the", "holograph", "of", "his", "organ", "concerto", "and", "a", "number", "of", "printed", "items", "."], "label": ["B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "regiment", "supported", "the", "1st", "Canadian", "Army", "for", "the", "first", "part", "of", "the", "battle", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Wall", "began", "work", "as", "a", "postdoctoral", "researcher", "at", "University", "of", "California-Riverside", "in", "1972", "where", "she", "began", "researching", "the", "function", "and", "biological", "diversity", "of", "soil", "ecosystems", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "barge", "dock", "was", "constructed", "at", "Kingston", "Railway", "Bridge", "close", "to", "the", "present", "the", "upstream", "entrance", "to", "Canbury", "Gardens", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "I-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "time", "progressed", "HDDs", "were", "able", "to", "store", "more", "information", "and", "the", "parts", "became", "much", "smaller", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["By", "comparison", ",", "the", "Sun", "takes", "almost", "a", "month", "to", "turn", "on", "its", "axis", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "combination", "of", "sweetness", ",", "citrus", ",", "and", "herbaceous", "mint", "flavours", "is", "intended", "to", "complement", "the", "rum", ",", "and", "has", "made", "the", "mojito", "a", "popular", "summer", "drink", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["WCD", "first", "came", "to", "prominence", "in", "the", "aftermath", "of", "the", "Deepwater", "Horizon", "Oil", "Spill", "to", "determine", "potential", "liability", "if", "another", "oil", "spill", "were", "to", "occur", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Thiamine", "in", "various", "salt", ",", "formulation", "and", "biological", "matrix", "forms", "are", "used", "to", "supplement", "human", "and", "animal", "diets", "because", "these", "organisms", "lack", "the", "capability", "to", "produce", "it", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "record", "three-day", "total", "of", "rain", "was", "recorded", "at", "Darwin", "International", "Airport", "due", "to", "the", "lingering", "of", "the", "system", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Most", "of", "Fogel", "'s", "projects", "have", "been", "in", "claymation", "ever", "since", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "``", "Star-News", "``", "never", "stopped", "publishing", "during", "the", "storm", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "total", ",", "it", "will", "be", "looking", "to", "sell", "$", "435", "million", "of", "its", "restaurants", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "finished", "statue", "of", "the", "Pioneer", "Woman", "Statue", "was", "high", "and", "weighed", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "sutra", "tells", "of", "how", "Kṣitigarbha", "became", "a", "bodhisattva", "by", "making", "great", "vows", "to", "rescue", "other", "sentient", "beings", "and", "a", "description", "of", "how", "he", "displayed", "filial", "piety", "in", "his", "past", "lifetimes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "journalism", "awards", "were", "presented", "the", "previous", "evening", "at", "the", "Grand", "Hyatt", "New", "York", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "result", "was", "that", "the", "World", "War", "II", "numbering", "of", "the", "original", "squadron", "was", "chosen", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "7", "March", "1941", ",", "the", "first", "Fairey-built", "Beaufighter", "Mk", "I", "performed", "its", "first", "test", "flight", ";", "the", "first", "Weston-built", "aircraft", "reached", "the", "same", "milestone", "on", "20", "February", "1941", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Characters", "from", "``", "Finding", "Nemo", "``", "appear", "as", "part", "of", "a", "minigame", "based", "on", "Finding", "Nemo", "Submarine", "Voyage", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "construction", "of", "the", "Vida", "Arena", "was", "finished", "in", "summer", "2011", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "DVD", "includes", "a", "behind-the-scenes", "special", ",", "``", "The", "Making", "of", "The", "Wiz", "Live", "!", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Through", "the", "day", ",", "she", "continued", "to", "shell", "those", "islands", ",", "and", ",", "in", "late", "afternoon", ",", "added", "Bennett", "Island", "to", "her", "targets", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "full", "title", "of", "the", "painting", "is", "Admonitions", "of", "the", "Court", "Instructress", "(", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["M62", "is", "equipped", "with", "electro-pneumatic", "multiple-unit", "controls", ";", "therefore", "it", "is", "possible", "to", "drive", "two", "locomotives", "from", "one", "cab", "."], "label": ["B-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Fort", "Denison", "Restaurant", "was", "opened", "on", "the", "island", "in", "2006", ",", "although", "the", "restaurant", "lease", "expired", "in", "June", "2017", "and", "is", "yet", "to", "be", "renewed", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "Revolution", "of", "1905", "he", "was", "an", "active", "participant", "of", "the", "strikes", "organised", "by", "his", "commilitodes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
