{"text": ["It", "is", "a", "Baffin", "Island", "offshore", "island", "located", "in", "Frobisher", "Bay", ",", "southeast", "of", "the", "capital", "city", "of", "Iqaluit", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sacred", "Heart", "Major", "Seminary", "offers", "a", "variety", "of", "academic", "programs", "for", "both", "clerical", "and", "lay", "students", "."], "label": ["B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1987", "and", "1991", "he", "finished", "third", "in", "a", "run", "for", "an", "African", "Footballer", "of", "the", "Year", "award", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "Apple", "computers", "also", "include", "some", "custom", "hardware", "and", "design", "choices", "not", "found", "in", "competing", "systems", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Harris", "worked", "extensively", "on", "and", "Off-Broadway", ",", "including", "a", "1989", "performance", "at", "Second", "Stage", "Theatre", "in", "``", "What", "a", "Man", "Weighs", "``", "."], "label": ["B-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O", "O", "B-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "I-art-music", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "accounted", "for", "roughly", "one", "third", "of", "the", "1st", "Hussars", "'", "dead", "over", "the", "entire", "war", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "arrested", "upon", "arrival", "at", "Stockholm", "Arlanda", "Airport", "on", "20", "March", "2017", "and", "was", "subsequently", "turned", "over", "to", "Finnish", "authorities", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-government/governmentagency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "every", "game", "where", "the", "Gators", "win", "he", "walks", "over", "with", "the", "team", "and", "the", "team", ",", "band", ",", "and", "fans", "sing", "the", "alma", "mater", "and", "the", "fight", "song", "together", "and", "the", "head", "coach", "shakes", "the", "director", "'s", "hand", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "event", "along", "with", "all", "speakers", "and", "interviews", "were", "broadcast", "live", "on", "the", "Pac-12", "Network", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "colonial", "times", ",", "those", "southern", "colonies", "were", "bastions", "of", "evangelical", ",", "even", "Calvinist", "sentiment", "among", "the", "Anglican", "clergy", "and", "gentry", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["One", "of", "the", "Dino", "206", "S", "chassis", "was", "used", "for", "the", "Ferrari", "212", "E", "Montagna", ",", "a", "uniquely-engined", ",", "one-off", "hillclimb-oriented", "sports", "car", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-car", "I-product-car", "I-product-car", "I-product-car", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "inscription", "contains", "3", "incomplete", "lines", ",", "comprising", "8", "complete", "words", "and", "fragments", "of", "5", "more", ",", "all", "written", "in", "the", "``", "Moabite", "language", "''", "known", "from", "only", "one", "other", "artifact", "-", "the", "Mesha", "Stele", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "opened", "in", "1907", "and", "was", "largely", "destroyed", "in", "1945", "in", "the", "closing", "days", "of", "World", "War", "II", ",", "though", "a", "small", "wing", "continued", "operating", "until", "1984", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Also", "in", "2008", ",", "they", "won", "the", "contract", "for", "re-developing", "three", "of", "the", "PS2", "Buzz", "!"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "results", "of", "the", "Gemini", "project", "were", "made", "available", "in", "early", "1998", "as", "UnixWare", "7", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "I-product-software", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "1700", "Cascadia", "earthquake", "caused", "near-shore", "subsidence", ",", "submerging", "marshes", "and", "forests", "on", "the", "coast", "that", "were", "later", "buried", "under", "more", "recent", "debris", "."], "label": ["O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "news", "of", "the", "problems", "there", "became", "public", ",", "the", "site", "was", "used", "by", "members", "of", "Congress", "as", "one", "of", "the", "reasons", "the", "proposed", "Superfund", "law", "was", "needed", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "The", "International", "Gilbert", "and", "Sullivan", "Festival", "was", "established", "in", "1994", ",", "he", "often", "performed", "and", "lectured", "for", "the", "festival", "'s", "audiences", "and", "held", "master", "classes", "for", "its", "performers", "."], "label": ["O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "made", "a", "special", "appearance", "in", "one", "episode", "of", "the", "series", "``", "Mujer", ",", "Casos", "de", "la", "Vida", "Real", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Insulin", "therapy", "is", "not", "the", "same", "as", "IPT", "low-dose", "chemotherapy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "has", "been", "performed", "by", "the", "Live", "Theatre", "Company", "and", "has", "received", "favourable", "reviews", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "a", "result", "of", "further", "increases", "in", "students", "and", "holdings", ",", "today", "'s", "library", "building", "was", "opened", "on", "North", "Street", "in", "1976", "where", "it", "now", "holds", "over", "a", "million", "books", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "has", "runs", "lessons", "for", "budding", "dart", "officials", "called", "``", "Jesus", "was", "a", "Scorer", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Some", "shortcomings", "of", "the", "Double", "Fairlie", "were", "identified", "during", "the", "trials", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "these", "reasons", ",", "and", "because", "of", "the", "important", "role", "it", "has", "repeatedly", "played", "in", "the", "modern", "era", ",", "SN", "1054", "is", "one", "of", "the", "best", "known", "supernovae", "in", "the", "history", "of", "astronomy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1925", ",", "the", "rates", "increased", "to", "1s", "8d", "in", "the", "£", ",", "three", "times", "that", "of", "the", "surrounding", "area", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Asia", "Park", "is", "also", "accessible", "by", "foot", "from", "the", "station", "."], "label": ["B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "book", "describes", "24-hours", "at", "the", "El", "Bulli", "restaurant", ",", "with", "images", ",", "commentary", ",", "photographs", "and", "30", "recipes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Karl", "Marx", "expressed", "disappointment", "at", "the", "bourgeois", "character", "of", "the", "revolutions", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Since", "August", "2019", ",", "she", "has", "been", "in", "a", "relationship", "with", "screenwriter", "Dylan", "Meyer", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "a", "decade", "after", "the", "Islamic", "revolution", "of", "1979", "all", "ashik", "performances", "were", "banned", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Leopard", "``", "served", "until", "1739", ",", "when", "she", "was", "broken", "up", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "then", "suspended", "for", "two", "seasons", "by", "the", "French", "Football", "Federation", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["Suggesting", "the", "Earl", "was", "a", "feared", "and", "respected", "opponent", "by", "this", "stage", "in", "the", "war", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "book", ",", "Crews", "detailed", "his", "long-standing", "pornography", "addiction", ",", "which", "had", "seriously", "affected", "his", "marriage", "and", "his", "life", ",", "but", "which", "he", "overcame", "around", "2009", "and", "2010", "after", "entering", "rehabilitation", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "most", "important", "feature", "is", "detecting", "a", "history", "of", "cannabinoid", "use", ",", "the", "denial", "of", "which", "can", "delay", "proper", "diagnosis", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "also", "helped", "lead", "the", "design", "team", "for", "the", "Walter", "E.", "Washington", "Convention", "Center", ",", "which", "opened", "in", "2003", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Some", "Beja", "groups", "have", "shifted", "to", "primary", "or", "exclusive", "use", "of", "Arabic", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O"]}
{"text": ["Northfield", "Mountains", "'", "geologic", "story", "can", "begin", "in", "the", "late", "pre-Cambrian", "Period", "."], "label": ["B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Under", "the", "MoU", ",", "a", "joint", "venture", "company", "would", "be", "set", "up", "to", "construct", "the", "airport", "suitable", "for", "operation", "of", "ATR-72", "type", "of", "aircraft", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2013", ",", "the", "National", "Library", "of", "Israel", "announced", "that", "it", "had", "purchased", "29", "pages", "from", "this", "cache", "of", "documents", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "May", "7", ",", "2007", ",", "a", "vehicle", "exploded", "in", "a", "Luxor", "Hotel", "parking", "garage", "due", "to", "a", "homemade", "pipe", "bomb", "which", "left", "one", "dead", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sobrasada", "(", ";", ")", "is", "a", "raw", ",", "cured", "sausage", "from", "the", "Balearic", "Islands", "made", "with", "ground", "pork", ",", "paprika", "and", "salt", "and", "other", "spices", "."], "label": ["B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["An", "untitled", "``", "Queen", "of", "Babble", "``", "movie", "is", "currently", "``", "in", "development", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "partially", "inspired", "by", "``", "Gulliver", "'s", "Travels", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O"]}
