{"text": ["The", "Para", "Brigade", "has", "been", "credited", "with", "numerous", "battles", "from", "Bangladesh", "Liberation", "War", "onwards", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Eighteen", "new", "monsters", "were", "developed", "for", "the", "game", ",", "and", "while", "there", "were", "only", "3", "of", "the", "same", "boss", "monsters", "from", "the", "previous", "games", "(", "Rathalos", ",", "Rathian", "and", "Diablos", ")", ",", "their", "interactive", "AI", "was", "completely", "redesigned", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["That", "remained", "the", "position", "until", "the", "aforementioned", "acts", "were", "repealed", "by", "the", "Visiting", "Forces", "Act", "1952", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O"]}
{"text": ["Late", "in", "the", "1980s", ",", "the", "loop", "was", "complete", "when", "Kota", "Bharu", "joined", "the", "grid", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "daughter", "was", "Isabella", ",", "a", "founder", "of", "Dunedin", "Public", "Art", "Gallery", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "I-building-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "by-election", "was", "won", "by", "Fraser", "Colman", ",", "also", "of", "the", "Labour", "Party", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pervez", "Hoodbhoy", ",", "a", "professor", "of", "nuclear", "physics", "at", "the", "Quaid-i-Azam", "University", "paid", "a", "tribute", "to", "him", "and", "said", ":"], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "authors", "dubbed", "it", "``", "The", "Swiss", "Army", "knife", "of", "Embedded", "Linux", "''", ",", "as", "the", "single", "executable", "replaces", "basic", "functions", "of", "more", "than", "300", "common", "commands", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "more", "than", "a", "year", "the", "monthly", "fee", "was", "2,995", "DKK", "(", ")", "per", "month", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "a", "result", ",", "it", "is", "a", "little", "less", "beamy", "and", "roomy", "than", "many", "other", "32", "footers", "on", "the", "used", "market", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pauahi", "Crater", "is", "a", "volcanic", "crater", "measuring", "long", ",", "up", "to", "some", "across", ",", "and", "deep", "in", "Hawaii", "Volcanoes", "National", "Park", "at", "."], "label": ["B-location-other", "I-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2003", ",", "he", "was", "signed", "by", "the", "Wichita", "Stealth", "of", "the", "AF2", "League", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "genome", "sequenced", "by", "shotgun", "sequencing", "was", "that", "of", "cauliflower", "mosaic", "virus", ",", "published", "in", "1981", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Transport", "systems", "have", "significant", "impacts", "on", "the", "environment", ",", "accounting", "for", "between", "20", "%", "and", "25", "%", "of", "world", "energy", "consumption", "and", "carbon", "dioxide", "emissions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "band", "was", "featured", "in", "episode", "seven", "of", "the", "comedic", "web", "series", ",", "``", "Nirvana", "the", "Band", "the", "Show", "``", ",", "playing", "as", "themselves", "as", "they", "rehearse", "with", "a", "new", "member", "of", "the", "band", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "I-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Over", "time", ",", "Crosby", "created", "a", "large", "number", "of", "monochrome", "works", "that", "were", "combined", "into", "a", "permanent", "exhibit", "at", "the", "Young", "Vic", "Theatre", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "I-building-theater", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Rinzai", "organisation", "includes", "fifteen", "subschools", "based", "on", "temple", "affiliation", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "August", "2004", ",", "HMG", "renamed", "itself", "RTL", "Nederl", "and", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "game", "was", "the", "second", "reboot", "of", "the", "``", "Spy", "Hunter", "``", "series", ",", "following", "the", "first", "reboot", "of", "the", "franchise", "in", "2001", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["But", "her", "name", "had", "been", "on", "a", "sheet", "of", "paper", "in", "the", "pocket", "of", "one", "of", "the", "men", "on", "death", "row", "connected", "to", "the", "Tokyo", "Subway", "attack", ",", "and", "her", "visa", "was", "denied", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Pang", "Jingtang", "(", ")", ",", "the", "Kuomintang", "party", "chief", "in", "Shandong", "as", "well", "as", "23", "other", "high-ranking", "Kuomintang", "officials", "were", "also", "captured", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "idea", "was", "to", "design", "and", "construct", "the", "Bengaluru", "Football", "Stadium", "like", "that", "but", "with", "a", "final", "capacity", "of", "90,000", "instead", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2001", ",", "a", "full", "service", "spa", "called", "``", "The", "Spa", "At", "The", "Hotel", "Hershey", "``", "was", "added", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Studies", "show", "that", "a", "woman", "who", "has", "had", "one", "child", "with", "a", "neural", "tube", "defect", "such", "as", "anencephaly", "has", "about", "a", "3", "%", "risk", "of", "having", "another", "child", "with", "a", "neural", "tube", "defect", ",", "as", "opposed", "to", "the", "background", "rate", "of", "0.1", "%", "occurrence", "in", "the", "population", "at", "large", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "locomotives", "were", "built", "to", "the", "specifications", "of", "LMS", "CME", "W.A", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "system", "is", "also", "located", "in", "the", "restaurant", "car", "of", "the", "ICE", "2", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Fo", "''", "is", "the", "Chinese", "word", "for", "``", "Buddha", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "Evo", "2011", ",", "a", "tournament", "season", "was", "announced", "in", "which", "players", "could", "earn", "ranking", "points", "at", "one", "of", "eight", "tournaments", "."], "label": ["O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Though", "only", "in", "length", ",", "The", "Salamander", "Glacier", "is", "about", "wide", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Another", "fainter", "visual", "companion", "listed", "as", "component", "D", "or", "Acrux", "D", ".", "A", "further", "seven", "faint", "stars", "are", "also", "listed", "as", "companions", "out", "to", "a", "distance", "of", "about", "two", "arc-minutes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Marston", "Science", "Library", "hosts", "the", "university", "'s", "extensive", "collections", "in", "agriculture", ",", "biological", "sciences", ",", "chemical", "and", "physical", "sciences", ",", "engineering", ",", "mathematics", "and", "statistics", "as", "well", "as", "librarians", "trained", "to", "help", "students", "and", "faculty", "working", "in", "these", "fields", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Da", "Vinci", "'s", "War", "is", "a", "1992", "direct", "to", "video", "action", "thriller", "film", "directed", "by", "Raymond", "Martino", "."], "label": ["B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "I-person-director", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "time", ",", "it", "was", "planned", "that", "the", "ESPN", "Zone", "restaurant", "would", "increase", "promotional", "efforts", "with", "the", "two", "sports", "teams", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "I-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "plotline", "was", ",", "however", ",", "quickly", "transplanted", "to", "a", "science-fictional", "setting", ",", "following", "the", "Piper", "Alpha", "disaster", "in", "1988", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Common", "names", "include", "lamb", "'s", "quarters", ",", "melde", ",", "goosefoot", ",", "manure", "weed", ",", "wild", "spinach", "and", "fat-hen", ",", "though", "the", "latter", "two", "are", "also", "applied", "to", "other", "species", "of", "the", "genus", "``", "Chenopodium", "``", ",", "for", "which", "reason", "it", "is", "often", "distinguished", "as", "white", "goosefoot", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Reruns", "aired", "on", "Nick", "at", "Nite", "from", "1985", "through", "1994", "and", "on", "TV", "Land", "from", "2002", "through", "2004", "."], "label": ["B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Hooker", "positioned", "three", "divisions", "opposite", "two", "peaks", "located", "one", "mile", "north", "of", "the", "gap", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1978", ",", "she", "was", "awarded", "the", "Women", "in", "Film", "Crystal", "Award", "for", "outstanding", "women", "who", ",", "through", "their", "endurance", "and", "the", "excellence", "of", "their", "work", ",", "have", "helped", "to", "expand", "the", "role", "of", "women", "within", "the", "entertainment", "industry", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Boeing", "Field", "in", "Seattle", "is", "one", "of", "the", "busiest", "primary", "non-hub", "airports", "in", "the", "U.S", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", ",", "and", "was", "demoed", "by", "Pet", "Shop", "Boys", "themselves", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "following", "two", "decades", "there", "were", "isolated", "cases", "identified", "mainly", "amongst", "Chinese", "and", "South", "Sea", "Islander", "people", "and", "the", "patients", "were", "either", "isolated", "on", "coastal", "islands", "or", "returned", "to", "their", "homelands", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "I-location-island", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "those", "events", "a", "museum", "dedicated", "to", "the", "Orange", "Revolution", "(", "``", "Pomarancheva", "Revolyuziya", "''", "-ukr", ".", ")"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "partially", "inspired", "by", "``", "Gulliver", "'s", "Travels", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O"]}
