{"text": ["or", "more", "formally", "as", "Henry", "Shapland", ",", "was", "known", "for", "participating", "in", "the", "design", "of", "over", "300", "golf", "courses", "around", "the", "globe", ",", "primarily", "in", "the", "United", "Kingdom", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-other", "I-person-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["De", "Constantia", "in", "publicis", "malis", "(", "On", "constancy", "in", "times", "of", "public", "evil", ")", "was", "a", "philosophical", "dialogue", "published", "by", "Justus", "Lipsius", "in", "two", "books", "in", "1583", "."], "label": ["B-art-writtenart", "I-art-writtenart", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author", "I-person-artist/author", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "then", "served", "the", "Royal", "Navy", "as", "HMS", "``", "Mohawk", "''", "until", "the", "Navy", "sold", "her", "in", "1814", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "I-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "August", "1962", "Queen", "Elizabeth", "II", "granted", "royal", "patronage", "to", "the", "APA", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "June", "1912", ",", "Congress", "appropriated", "$", "100,000", "to", "dredge", "the", "Anacostia", "from", "the", "11th", "Street", "Bridges", "to", "the", "District-Maryland", "line", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "recent", "tendency", "has", "been", "to", "attribute", "these", "works", "to", "anonymous", "``", "Pseudo-", "Salini", "``", "painters", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Odus", "Creamer", "Horney", "was", "an", "officer", "of", "the", "U.S", "Army", "from", "1891", "to", "1930", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "I-person-soldier", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Use", "of", "these", "drugs", "has", "been", "associated", "with", "a", "decrease", "in", "depression", "and", "increased", "functioning", "in", "social", "and", "work", "environments", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Winners", "of", "the", "award", "are", "also", "nominated", "for", "the", "Brian", "Kilrea", "Coach", "of", "the", "Year", "Award", "for", "the", "Canadian", "Hockey", "League", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "1", "June", "2013", ",", "a", "helicopter", "ferry", "service", "was", "started", "at", "IIT", "Kanpur", "run", "by", "Pawan", "Hans", "Helicopters", "Limited", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "I-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Although", "the", "Broncos", "did", "not", "receive", "all", "first-place", "votes", "in", "the", "coaches", "'", "poll", ",", "their", "selection", "was", "effectively", "unanimous", ";", "league", "rules", "prohibit", "coaches", "from", "casting", "first-place", "votes", "for", "their", "own", "teams", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Other", "major", "highways", "that", "link", "other", "parts", "of", "the", "Island", "to", "the", "main", "highways", "of", "Kauaʻi", "are", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kennesaw", "Battlefield", "Park", "preserves", "a", "Civil", "War", "battleground", "of", "the", "Atlanta", "Campaign", ",", "and", "also", "contains", "Kennesaw", "Mountain", "."], "label": ["B-location-park", "I-location-park", "I-location-park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O"]}
{"text": ["Fentanyl", "intoxication", "and", "recent", "methamphetamine", "use", "might", "have", "increased", "the", "likelihood", "of", "death", "."], "label": ["B-other-medical", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Federal", "Data", "Services", "Hub", "is", "a", "tool", "used", "to", "facilitate", "the", "government-backed", "Patient", "Protection", "and", "Affordable", "Care", "Act", "health", "coverage", "program", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sunset", "Boulevard", "raised", "the", "most", "money", ",", "followed", "by", "Sunday", "in", "the", "Park", "with", "George", "and", "Dear", "Evan", "Hansen", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "codex", "remains", "at", "the", "Uppsala", "University", "Library", "in", "the", "Carolina", "Rediviva", "building", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Much", "of", "what", "is", "understood", "about", "the", "normal", "function", "of", "DISC1", "has", "been", "uncovered", "through", "studies", "on", "zebrafish", "and", "mice", "as", "model", "organisms", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", ".30", "Remington", "cartridge", "was", "created", "in", "1906", "by", "Remington", "Arms", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "best", "known", "as", "a", "member", "of", "the", "boyband", "NSYNC", ",", "in", "which", "he", "sang", "baritone", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["About", "100", "kilometres", "south-east", "of", "the", "commune", ",", "Bordeaux", "-", "Merignac", "Airport", "is", "an", "international", "airport", "with", "connections", "to", "many", "countries", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "2013", "video", "presentation", "can", "be", "viewed", "on", "the", "school", "'s", "YouTube", "page", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Today", ",", "however", ",", "many", "linguists", "regard", "Haida", "as", "a", "language", "isolate", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "company", "started", "with", "flights", "charter", ",", "with", "3", "rented", "Boeing", "727-200", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "star", "is", "radiating", "1,592", "times", "the", "Sun", "'s", "luminosity", "from", "its", "enlarged", "photosphere", "at", "an", "effective", "temperature", "of", "5,300", "K.", "It", "is", "a", "source", "of", "X-ray", "emission", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dr.", "Spock", "was", "the", "Party", "'s", "candidate", "for", "vice", "president", "."], "label": ["B-person-scholar", "I-person-scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "an", "explanation", "of", "the", "U.S.", "presidential", "election", "process", "see", "U.S", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "history", "of", "documents", ",", "newsletters", "and", "programs", "can", "be", "found", "at", "Black", "Eagle", "Lodge", "482", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O"]}
{"text": ["While", "the", "Westword", "says", "the", "album", "``", "underwhelms", ",", "''", "The", "Post-Star", "calls", "this", "album", "``", "the", "most", "intriguing", "offering", "''", "among", "2007", "'s", "country", "music", "Christmas", "releases", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "approached", "from", "behind", "and", "shot", "several", "times", "in", "the", "back", "by", "an", "Islamic", "extremist", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "final", "but", "detailed", "record", "of", "ninja", "employed", "in", "open", "warfare", "occurred", "during", "the", "Shimabara", "Rebellio", "n", "(", "1637–1638", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "art", ",", "Khnum", "was", "usually", "depicted", "as", "a", "ram-headed", "man", "at", "a", "potter", "'s", "wheel", ",", "with", "recently", "created", "children", "'s", "bodies", "standing", "on", "the", "wheel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "the", "response", "had", "amassed", "85,000", "retweets", "and", "300,000", "likes", ",", "Popeyes", "chains", "began", "to", "sell", "many", "more", "sandwiches", "to", "the", "point", "where", "many", "locations", "sold", "all", "of", "their", "stock", "of", "chicken", "sandwiches", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "music", "video", ",", "Carey", "plays", "her", "part", "as", "a", "cabaret", "girl", ",", "dancing", "on", "a", "chair", "accompanied", "by", "two", "other", "females", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Cutty", "Sark", "``", "whisky", "derives", "its", "name", "from", "the", "ship", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-food", "I-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "a", "contestant", "on", "the", "show", "``", "Dadagiri", "``", ",", "when", "an", "altercation", "took", "place", "that", "became", "popularized", "by", "meme", "culture", "as", "``", "How", "can", "she", "slap", "?", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "formerly", "known", "as", "SP", "3399", ",", "3472", ",", "and", "5639", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Moses", "Mabhida", "Stadium", "was", "completed", "in", "2009", "and", "involved", "massive", "regeneration", "of", "the", "surrounding", "infrastructure", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "single", "was", "used", "as", "an", "image", "song", "for", "PlayStation", "portable", "game", "``", "Monster", "Rancher", "2", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Floodwaters", "from", "the", "stream", "during", "Hurricane", "Diane", "in", "1955", "damaged", "low-lying", "land", "in", "the", "borough", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "full", "title", "of", "the", "painting", "is", "Admonitions", "of", "the", "Court", "Instructress", "(", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "I-art-painting", "O", "O", "O"]}
