{"text": ["With", "the", "onset", "of", "the", "Second", "World", "War", "Walker", "joined", "the", "Royal", "Air", "Force", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "B-person-soldier", "O", "O", "B-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "I-organization-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "lost", "in", "the", "next", "round", "to", "J", "oshua", "Filler", ",", "11–1", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Almost", "a", "century", "later", ",", "the", "Association", "of", "Religion", "Data", "Archives", "(", "relying", "on", "World", "Christian", "Encyclopedia", ")", "estimated", "some", "15,700", "Baháʼís", "in", "2005", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "I-organization-religion", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "the", "same", "day", ",", "a", "total", "of", "three", "locations", "in", "Baghdad", "housing", "journalists", "were", "fired", "upon", "by", "U.S.", "armed", "forces", ",", "killing", "three", "journalists", "and", "wounding", "four", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "supports", "creating", "customized", "assertion", "matchers", "(", "'", "Hamcrest", "'", "is", "an", "anagram", "of", "'matchers", "'", ")", ",", "allowing", "match", "rules", "to", "be", "defined", "declaratively", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "large", "bull", "statue", "advertises", "their", "``", "free", "''", "72", "oz", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "management", "of", "low", "back", "pain", "often", "includes", "medications", "for", "the", "duration", "that", "they", "are", "beneficial", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "I-other-disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Instead", "of", "a", "conventional", "keyboard", ",", "the", "Taurus", "uses", "an", "organ-style", "pedal", "board", "similar", "to", "the", "pedal", "keyboard", "of", "a", "spinet", "organ", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Painter", "Wing", ",", "built", "in", "1913", ",", "is", "the", "oldest", "existing", "portion", "of", "the", "hotel", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-other", "I-building-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Gimnasia", "y", "Esgrima", "de", "Mendoza", "lost", "the", "play-off", "match", "on", "penalties", "and", "were", "relegated", "."], "label": ["B-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "I-organization-sportsteam", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Marles", "Variomatic", "is", "the", "trademark", "name", "of", "an", "automotive", "power", "steering", "system", "of", "the", "1960s", "and", "70s", ",", "which", "was", "characterised", "by", "its", "variable", "steering", "ratio", "."], "label": ["B-organization-company", "I-organization-company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "Colombian", "presidential", "election", "of", "2002", "she", "ran", "as", "Vice", "Presidential", "candidate", "for", "Luis", "Eduardo", "Garzón", "in", "the", "Social", "and", "Political", "Front", "ticket", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "I-event-election", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Doubtful", "Sound", "bottlenoses", "have", "formed", "a", "very", "insular", "subgroup", "of", "only", "about", "70", "individuals", ",", "with", "none", "having", "been", "observed", "to", "leave", "or", "enter", "the", "Sound", "during", "a", "multi-year", "monitoring", "regime", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "I-other-biologything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "size", "of", "the", "two", "main", "stars", "in", "the", "Eta", "Carinae", "system", "is", "difficult", "to", "determine", "precisely", "because", "neither", "star", "can", "be", "seen", "directly", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "destroyed", "in", "the", "1755", "Lisbon", "earthquake", "and", "fragments", "of", "it", "are", "housed", "in", "the", "church", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "I-event-disaster", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "Waitrose", "supermarket", "opened", "opposite", "the", "theatre", "in", "August", "2013", ",", "along", "with", "a", "Travelodge", "Hotel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel", "I-building-hotel", "O"]}
{"text": ["W.", "K.", "Kellogg", "persuaded", "his", "brother", "to", "serve", "the", "food", "in", "flake", "form", "."], "label": ["B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Four", "of", "his", "five", "policy", "recommendations", "were", "incorporated", "into", "the", "U.S.", "Federal", "Financial", "Law", "of", "1966", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Route", "38", "surrounds", "most", "of", "the", "Mall", "at", "Rockingham", "Park", "."], "label": ["B-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-park", "I-location-park", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", ",", "incorrectly", "using", "a", "Scottish", "accent", "as", "he", "did", "so", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "were", "awarded", "the", "Gold", "Plaque", "Award", "for", "their", "performance", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "tenure", "he", "presided", "over", "the", "1981", "Karpov–Korchnoi", "World", "Championship", "match", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-other", "I-event-other", "I-event-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "completed", "two-tier", "bowl", "stadium", "would", "give", "Celtic", "Park", "a", "capacity", "of", "nearly", "75,000", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-sportsfacility", "I-building-sportsfacility", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "the", "fifth", "game", "in", "the", "``", "Colin", "McRae", "Rally", "``", "series", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-game", "I-product-game", "I-product-game", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "guest-conducted", "a", "Cleveland", "Orchestra", "performance", "on", "2", "August", "1958", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization", "I-organization-showorganization", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Before", "that", ",", "the", "residents", "survived", "by", "fishing", ",", "limited", "trading", ",", "and", "salvage", "of", "ships", "wrecked", "on", "Elbow", "Reef", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island", "I-location-island", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bratislava", "'s", "M.", "R.", "Štefánik", "Airport", "is", "the", "main", "and", "largest", "international", "airport", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "I-building-airport", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Although", "he", "worked", "on", "Pride", "of", "the", "Yankees", "in", "1933–34", ",", "he", "refused", "credits", "as", "he", "did", "on", "several", "other", "pictures", "and", "unfinished", "projects", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "I-art-film", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "main", "target", "for", "the", "season", "was", "to", "win", "the", "UEFA", "Champions", "League", ",", "which", "it", "failed", "when", "it", "got", "knocked", "out", "in", "the", "second", "group", "stage", ",", "rendering", "better", "form", "in", "the", "league", "when", "it", "did", "not", "have", "to", "rest", "players", "in", "those", "matches", "anymore", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Now", "in", "the", "Avon", "Gorge", ",", "the", "railway", "runs", "through", "No", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-mountain", "I-location-mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Carbon", "monoxide", "poisoning", "is", "the", "most", "common", "type", "of", "fatal", "air", "poisoning", "in", "many", "countries", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing", "I-other-chemicalthing", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "1:10", "scale", "``", "Titanic", "``", "model", "was", "one", "of", "the", "main", "attractions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Silvaner", "at", "8.1", "%", "is", "also", "widely", "planted", ",", "although", "it", "also", "has", "decreased", "significantly", "."], "label": ["B-product-food", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "he", "was", "about", "forty", ",", "the", "Yuan-Chao", "Rebellion", "broken", "broke", "out", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-protest", "I-event-protest", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Mistick", "Krewe", "of", "Comus", "presented", "a", "parade", "annually", "on", "the", "evening", "of", "Shrove", "Tuesday", "from", "1857", "to", "1991", "with", "the", "only", "exception", "being", "during", "war", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "I-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "show", "originally", "had", "the", "working", "title", "of", "``", "Bellamy", "'s", "Kingdom", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "unusual", "for", "a", "``", "menologion", "``", "from", "that", "era", "to", "be", "so", "richly", "painted", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "trait", "most", "often", "associated", "with", "the", "Contessa", "32", "though", "is", "its", "ability", "to", "endure", "harsh", "weather", "and", "rough", "seas", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-airplane", "I-product-airplane", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "new", "building", "contained", "the", "Trumbull", "dining", "hall", ",", "common", "room", ",", "and", "library", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "numerous", "DRB", "Class", "50", "(", "2-10-0", ")", "locomotives", ",", "for", "example", ",", "were", "capable", "of", "in", "either", "direction", ",", "and", "were", "commonly", "used", "on", "branch", "lines", "without", "turning", "facilities", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-product-train", "I-product-train", "I-product-train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "reopened", "to", "readers", "as", "the", "Weston", "Library", "on", "21", "March", "2015", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-library", "I-building-library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
