{"text": ["While", "at", "Union", ",", "he", "co-founded", "the", "Institute", "for", "Art", ",", "Religion", "and", "Social", "Justice", "with", "Kathryn", "Reklis", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "expansion", "season", "of", "1967–68", ",", "the", "Red", "Wings", "acquired", "longtime", "star", "left-winger", "Frank", "Mahovlich", "from", "the", "defending", "Cup", "champions", "in", "Toronto", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["KG", "3", "was", "created", "in", "1939", "as", "the", "Luftwaffe", "reorganised", "and", "expanded", "to", "meet", "Adolf", "Hitler", "'s", "rearmament", "demands", "."], "label": ["B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "USS", "``", "Estero", "``", "(", "CVE-42", ")", "(", "previously", "AVG-42", "then", "later", "ACV-42", ")", "was", "an", "escort", "aircraft", "carrier", "launched", "22", "March", "1943", "by", "the", "Seattle-Tacoma", "Shipbuilding", "Corporation", ",", "Seattle", ",", "Washington", ",", "and", "sponsored", "by", "Mrs.", "C.", "N.", "Ingraham", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "particular", ",", "norepinephrine", "decreases", "glutamatergic", "excitatory", "postsynaptic", "potentials", "by", "the", "activation", "of", "α1-adrenergic", "receptors", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "also", "president", "of", "the", "Fetia", "Api", "political", "party", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1986", ",", "Martin", "engaged", "then-Governor", "and", "future", "President", "Bill", "Clinton", "in", "a", "debate", "before", "the", "United", "States", "Senate", "Committee", "on", "Energy", "and", "Natural", "Resources", "on", "the", "merits", "of", "the", "Federal", "Energy", "Regulatory", "Commission", "'s", "powers", "to", "set", "interstate", "electricity", "rates", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Faustus", "Cornelius", "Sulla", "was", "a", "Roman", "senator", "who", "lived", "during", "the", "reign", "of", "the", "emperor", "Tiberius", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Sarasaviya", "Best", "Director", "Award", "is", "presented", "annually", "by", "the", "weekly", "Sarasaviya", "newspaper", "in", "collaboration", "with", "the", "Associated", "Newspapers", "of", "Ceylon", "Limited", "as", "part", "of", "the", "Sarasaviya", "Awards", "Festival", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Harry", "and", "Penelope", "Seidler", "House", "at", "13", "Kalang", "Avenue", "was", "designed", "by", "Harry", "and", "Penelope", "Seidler", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["for", "research", "in", "quantum", "chemistry", ",", "he", "joined", "the", "research", "staff", "of", "the", "British", "Rubber", "Producers", "Research", "Association", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "monograph", "was", "published", "after", "a", "diagnosis", "of", "metastatic", "stage", "IV", "breast", "cancer", "in", "2009", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "second", "round", ",", "the", "Wranglers", "selected", "Mashona", "Washington", "and", "left", "Ahsha", "Rolle", "unprotected", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Water", "from", "the", "Sterkfontein", "Dam", "is", "released", "once", "the", "Vaal", "Dam", "drops", "to", "below", "16", "%", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "airline", "was", "purchased", "by", "China", "Eastern", "Airlines", "in", "May", "2001", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "December", "1942", ",", "it", "went", "into", "production", "with", "the", "M2", "Half", "Track", "Car", "and", "M3", "Half-track", "versions", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "that", "time", ",", "City", "Island", "was", "only", "available", "for", "Android", "devices", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "soundtrack", "also", "contains", "music", "not", "used", "in", "the", "game", ",", "including", "a", "variation", "on", "the", "Halo", "theme", "that", "was", "first", "played", "at", "``", "Halo", "``", "s", "debut", "at", "Macworld", "1999", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Royal", "Danish", "Library", "has", "a", "daguerreotype", "of", "Høegh-Guldberg", "sitting", "with", "3", "of", "his", "children", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Homocysteine", "inhibits", "lysyl", "oxidase", "which", "is", "responsible", "for", "post-translational", "modifications", "of", "collagen", ",", "a", "key", "component", "to", "bone", "structure"], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "official", "exchange", "rate", "for", "the", "United", "States", "dollar", "hovered", "around", "3:1", "from", "2002", "to", "2008", ",", "climbing", "from", "6:1", "to", "10:1", "between", "2009", "and", "2015", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["CloudBees", "provides", "commercial", "support", "and", "additional", "plugins", "for", "open", "source", "Jenkins", "."], "label": ["B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "group", "'s", "name", "was", "inspired", "by", "Rose", "McGowan", "'s", "character", "in", "the", "1995", "Gregg", "Araki", "movie", "``", "The", "Doom", "Generation", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "milk", "analogues", "lack", "the", "vitamins", "or", "dietary", "minerals", "present", "in", "dairy", "milk", "(", "such", "as", "vitamin", "B12", "or", "calcium", ")", ",", "they", "may", "be", "fortified", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["DP", "World", "awarded", "ENVIRON", "the", "Golden", "Dhow", "Award", "for", "its", "environmental", "consultancy", "services", "to", "the", "London", "Gateway", "super", "port", "."], "label": ["B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Thereafter", ",", "operator", "Plains", "All", "American", "Pipeline", "was", "indicted", "on", "46", "criminal", "charges", "related", "to", "the", "spill", ",", "with", "one", "employee", "indicted", "on", "three", "criminal", "charges", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "many", "Indigenous", "people", ",", "the", "Buffalo", "is", "not", "sleeping", "anymore", "since", "Banff", "National", "Park", "reintroduced", "wild", "bison", "in", "2017", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kuching", "International", "Airport", "(", "KCH", ")", "(", "ICAO", "Code", ":", "WBGG", ")", "is", "the", "main", "gateway", "for", "air", "passengers", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "The", "Latehomecomer", "``", "is", "a", "National", "Endowment", "of", "the", "Arts", "'", "Big", "Read", "book", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "I-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "2010", ",", "she", "collaborated", "with", "writer/director", "J.B.", "Ghuhman", "Jr", ".", "and", "music", "producer", "Yeti", "Beats", "on", "the", "soundtrack", "of", "the", "award-winning", "movie", "``", "Spork", "``", ",", "which", "incorporated", "many", "references", "to", "1990s", "pop-culture", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "2012", "Blossom", "Kite", "festival", "took", "place", "on", "the", "Washington", "Monument", "grounds", "on", "Saturday", ",", "March", "31", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "won", "the", "Gerald", "Lampert", "Award", "in", "1998", "for", "his", "poetry", "collection", "``", "The", "Landing", "``", ",", "and", "the", "Toronto", "Book", "Award", "in", "2010", "for", "his", "novel", "``", "The", "Carnivore", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "I-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "I-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Bangladesh", "Hospital", "was", "a", "temporary", "medical", "centre", "under", "the", "Sector-2", "during", "the", "Liberation", "War", "of", "Bangladesh", "in", "1971", "."], "label": ["B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "graduated", "from", "Harvard", "University", "Medical", "School", "in", "1918", "and", "founded", "his", "own", "medical", "practice", "a", "few", "years", "later", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "effective", "temperature", "of", "the", "star", "'s", "chromosphere", "is", "5,911", "K", ",", "giving", "it", "a", "yellow-hued", "glow", "like", "the", "Sun", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["Every", "observation", "is", "honed", "to", "perfection", "''", "and", "BBC", "6", "Music", "DJ", "Steve", "Lamacq", "described", "David", "as", "``", "Part", "Stiff", "Records", ",", "part", "Brit", "Pop", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Treaty", "of", "Medicine", "Lodge", "moved", "the", "Kiowa", "onto", "a", "reservation", "and", "promised", "annuities", "of", "food", ",", "clothes", ",", "equipment", ",", "weapons", ",", "and", "ammunition", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "seemed", "as", "if", "WMU", "found", "the", "spring", "it", "needed", "for", "a", "rebound", "as", "the", "team", "posted", "a", "6–6", "record", "in", "2010", ",", "though", "it", "was", "not", "selected", "for", "a", "bowl", "game", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Prior", "to", "the", "election", ",", "Russell", "hired", "extra", "riders", "to", "ensure", "that", "fresh", "riders", "and", "relay", "horses", "were", "available", "along", "the", "route", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["El", "amor", "brujo", "is", "a", "piece", "of", "music", "originally", "composed", "by", "Manuel", "de", "Falla", "for", "a", "chamber", "group", "."], "label": ["B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "lived", "on", "St.", "Simons", "from", "1965", "until", "her", "death", "in", "1996", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Per", "Constitution", "of", "India", ",", "Meitei", "language", "is", "among", "the", "languages", "specified", "in", "the", "Schedule", "VIII", "of", "the", "Constitution", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Integrated", "Farm", "Management", "Program", "(", "IFMP", ")", "was", "a", "program", "authorized", "by", "the", "1990", "farm", "bill", "(", "P.L", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Starting", "in", "2016", ",", "KXMA", "moved", "CBS", "programming", "to", "its", "second", "digital", "subchannel", ",", "with", "The", "CW", "on", "its", "primary", "channel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "also", "named", "in", "the", "2003", "Super", "League", "Dream", "Team", "at", "fullback", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Semisopochnoi", "Island", "also", "supports", "a", "significant", "population", "of", "red-faced", "cormorants", "."], "label": ["B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "23", "June", ",", "at", "the", "start", "of", "the", "major", "Soviet", "Operation", "Bagration", "offensive", ",", "it", "formed", "part", "of", "Army", "Group", "Centre", "'s", "reserve", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "addition", "to", "performing", "seven", "pairs", "of", "classical", "concerts", "each", "season", ",", "the", "Symphony", "also", "entertains", "with", "New", "Year", "'s", "Eve", "Pops", "and", "its", "annual", "Yankee", "Doodle", "Pops", "concerts", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Thus", "Gwanaksan", "literally", "means", "``", "mountain", "of", "the", "hat-shaped", "peak", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["NGC", "6584", "is", "a", "globular", "cluster", "in", "the", "constellation", "Telescopium", "that", "lies", "near", "Theta", "Arae", "and", "is", "45000", "light-years", "distant", "."], "label": ["B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["All", "three", "crew", "members", "had", "visited", "the", "International", "Space", "Station", "together", "in", "May", "2000", "aboard", "STS-101", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "a", "month-long", "investigation", "in", "December", "2005", "and", "testing", "in", "January", "2006", ",", "new", "operating", "procedures", "were", "developed", "that", "would", "allow", "Landsat", "5", "to", "continue", "normal", "operations", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["McGovern", "Medical", "School", "provides", "faculty", ",", "residents", ",", "and", "students", "for", "Memorial", "Hermann-Texas", "Medical", "Center", "and", "Lyndon", "Baines", "Johnson", "General", "Hospital", "."], "label": ["B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "O", "B-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "24", "May", ",", "he", "scored", "two", "goals", "in", "a", "4-0", "win", "against", "Western", "Pride", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "piscides", "are", "used", ",", "antimycin", "is", "often", "the", "preferred", "choice", "as", "there", "is", "little", "impact", "on", "lake", "invertebrates", "and", "its", "toxicity", "naturally", "subsides", "before", "reaching", "fish", "populations", "downstream", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "dedicated", "to", "Proserpina", ",", "goddess", "of", "the", "underworld", "and", "renewal", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Rigden", "``", ",", "wylie", ":", "``", "rigs", "ldan", "``", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Against", "the", "wishes", "of", "the", "Treaty", "8", "Caravan", ",", "logging", "and", "land", "clearing", "for", "the", "dam", "began", "in", "2015", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "powered", "by", "a", "16-cylinder", "EMD", "645F3B", "diesel", "engine", ",", "which", "can", "produce", "between", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "film", "originally", "aired", "on", "NBC", "on", "June", "16", ",", "1976", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "many", "of", "the", "works", ",", "including", "the", "operas", "``", "Maskarade", "``", "and", "``", "Saul", "and", "David", "``", ",", "and", "the", "complete", "``", "Aladdin", "``", "music", ",", "this", "was", "their", "first", "printed", "publication", ",", "copies", "of", "manuscripts", "having", "previously", "been", "used", "in", "performances", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "provincial", "dominant", "language", "is", "Pashto", "and", "Dari", "(", "Afghan", "Persian", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "cantons", "resumed", "minting", "their", "own", "coins", "from", "1806", ",", "now", "mostly", "denominated", "in", "``", "francs", "``", ",", "with", "one", "Swiss", "franc", "equal", "to", "1.5", "French", "francs", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O"]}
{"text": ["Skell", "fought", "with", "Spirit", "of", "the", "Below-World", ",", "Llao", ",", "who", "resided", "at", "Mount", "Mazama", "by", "throwing", "hot", "rocks", "and", "lava", ",", "probably", "representing", "the", "volcanic", "eruptions", "at", "both", "mountains", "."], "label": ["B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1974", ",", "she", "received", "her", "Juris", "doctor", "from", "the", "University", "of", "Puerto", "Rico", "School", "of", "Law", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-educationaldegree", "I-other-educationaldegree", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "seeing", "action", "during", "the", "Irish", "Rebellion", "of", "1798", "he", "took", "part", "in", "the", "Battle", "of", "Copenhagen", "during", "the", "Napoleonic", "Wars", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O"]}
{"text": ["Having", "experienced", "sexism", "in", "her", "workplace", ",", "``", "being", "fondled", ",", "being", "pushed", "against", "the", "wall", "''", ",", "she", "wanted", "to", "create", "job", "opportunities", "for", "women", "with", "dependents", ",", "and", "predominantly", "employed", "women", ",", "with", "only", "three", "male", "programmers", "in", "the", "first", "300", "staff", ",", "until", "the", "Sex", "Discrimination", "Act", "1975", "made", "that", "practice", "illegal", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "first", "Holmenkollen", "Ski", "Festival", "of", "1892", "he", "finished", "second", "in", "the", "Nordic", "combined", "contest", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "TT", "Nagar", "Sport", "Complex", "is", "also", "located", "near", "the", "school", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["previously", "played", "on", "three", "different", "grounds", "at", "Eirias", "Park", "during", "their", "history", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "also", "helped", "lead", "the", "design", "team", "for", "the", "Walter", "E.", "Washington", "Convention", "Center", ",", "which", "opened", "in", "2003", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Critics", "have", "pointed", "out", "an", "elusive", "state", "of", "the", "country", "'s", "development", "as", "the", "period", "is", "marred", "by", "a", "sharp", "devaluing", "of", "the", "Philippine", "Peso", "from", "3.9", "to", "20.53", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "local", "record", ",", "``", "Avia", "Ripensis", "``", "(", ")", ",", "mentions", "the", "existence", "of", "a", "local", "church", "in", "1340", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "story", "'s", "details", "were", "featured", "on", "Doctor", "Who", "Magazine", "issue", "255", ",", "in", "August", "1997", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Among", "these", "developments", "include", "The", "Venetian", ",", "Mandalay", "Bay", ",", "and", "Paris", "Las", "Vegas", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O"]}
{"text": ["Serving", "seasonal", "dishes", ",", "the", "Daily", "Dose", "sources", "the", "ingredients", "that", "are", "locally", "grown", "and", "harvested", "by", "regional", "farms", ",", "farmer", "'s", "markets", ",", "and", "bakeries", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "Iranian", "Revolution", "of", "1979", ",", "before", "the", "fall", "of", "the", "government", ",", "he", "believed", "that", "religion", "should", "not", "be", "involved", "in", "politics", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "abdicated", "on", "22", "November", "1918", ",", "amidst", "the", "tumults", "of", "the", "German", "Revolution", "of", "1918–19", "which", "resulted", "in", "the", "abolition", "of", "the", "Grand", "Duchy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Both", "military", "and", "police", "are", "the", "first", "to", "introduce", "Lingala", "in", "this", "territory", "during", "various", "conflicts", "among", "groupings", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
