{"text": ["It", "is", "visible", "from", "as", "far", "away", "as", "Sandia", "Crest", "near", "Albuquerque", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "then", "worked", "as", "a", "cameraman", "at", "Métropole", "Télévision", ",", "France", "3", ",", "TV5MONDE", "and", "CFI", "before", "creating", "the", "1994", "short", "film", "``", "Un", "taxi", "pour", "Aouzou", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "spite", "of", "this", "confirmation", ",", "some", "plantings", "of", "true", "Dolcetto", "vines", "still", "retain", "the", "local", "synonyms", "in", "some", "areas", "of", "Savoie", "and", "California", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "causeway", "and", "adjacent", "Mcgees", "Bridge", "provide", "vital", "links", "between", "Hobart", "and", "two", "of", "Tasmania", "'s", "principal", "tourist", "attractions", "-", "Port", "Arthur", "Historic", "Site", "on", "the", "Tasman", "Peninsula", "and", "the", "picturesque", "East", "Coast", "via", "the", "Tasman", "Highway", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Despite", "a", "spirited", "defense", "by", "the", "Confederates", ",", "the", "position", "was", "quickly", "overrun", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["According", "to", "Strabo", ",", "Seleucus", "Nicator", "gave", "these", "regions", "to", "Chandragupta", "along", "with", "a", "marriage", "treaty", ",", "and", "in", "return", "received", "five", "hundred", "elephants", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Strikers", ",", "with", "Laughlin", "in", "the", "team", "went", "on", "to", "win", "the", "tournament", ",", "their", "first", "BBL", "title", "."], "label": ["B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Although", "it", "did", "not", "win", "any", "Academy", "Awards", ",", "it", "did", ",", "in", "fact", ",", "receive", "eight", "nominations", "–", "including", "one", "for", "Rozsa", "'s", "score", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "outgoing", "mail", ",", "specific", "postage", "stamps", "would", "be", "issued", "even", "if", "the", "Australian", "Department", "of", "Territories", "asked", "the", "Australian", "post", "office", "to", "produce", "them", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "statement", "by", "the", "Air", "Force", "of", "Iran", "'s", "Islamic", "Revolution", "Guards", "Corps", "(", "IRGC", ")", "stated", "that", "Ali", "Al", "Salem", "Air", "Base", "in", "Kuwait", "participated", ",", "among", "other", "bases", "in", "the", "region", ",", "in", "the", "operation", "that", "was", "executed", "near", "Baghdad", "airport", "recently", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Maine", "Medical", "Center", "is", "owned", "by", "MaineHealth", ",", "the", "state", "'s", "largest", "healthcare", "organization", "."], "label": ["B-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "I-building-hospital", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "One", "Fish", ",", "Two", "Fish", ",", "Blowfish", ",", "Blue", "Fish", "``", "is", "the", "eleventh", "episode", "of", "``", "The", "Simpsons", "``", "'", "second", "season", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "released", "on", "October", "14", ",", "2008", "and", "could", "only", "be", "obtained", "from", "Club", "Nintendo", "for", "400", "coins", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Lockhart", "has", "also", "served", "as", "President", "of", "the", "Actors", "'", "Fund", "of", "Canada", "."], "label": ["B-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "creation", "of", "the", "vehicles", "was", "overseen", "by", "guard", "member", "Captain", "Mišel", "Ostojić", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "expeditions", "between", "1947", "and", "1957", "in", "the", "area", "of", "Anti-Taurus", "Mountains", "and", "Amanos", "Mountains", "led", "him", "the", "discovery", "of", "an", "ancient", "trail", "network", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "Vice-President", "and", "General", "Manager", "of", "GTR", "he", "is", "credited", "with", "keeping", "the", "company", "from", "bankruptcy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["That", "game", "was", "against", "Footscray", "at", "Western", "Ova", "l", "in", "round", "nine", "and", "he", "had", "six", "disposals", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Siya", "'s", "life", "is", "saved", ",", "and", "life", "seemingly", "returns", "to", "normal", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sabouraud", "agar", "or", "Sabouraud", "dextrose", "agar", "(", "SDA", ")", "is", "a", "type", "of", "agar", "growth", "medium", "containing", "peptones", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Kempf", "coined", "the", "term", "``", "homosexual", "panic", "``", "for", "the", "condition", ",", "and", "classified", "it", "as", "an", "acute", "pernicious", "dissociative", "disorder", ",", "meaning", "that", "it", "involved", "a", "disruption", "in", "typical", "perception", "and", "memory", "functions", "."], "label": ["B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Hamilton", "Fish", "(", "W", ")", "was", "elected", "Lieutenant", "Governor", ";", "and", "all", "the", "other", "eleven", "statewide", "elective", "offices", "were", "won", "by", "the", "Whigs", "."], "label": ["B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Game", "Machine", "``", "listed", "``", "Space", "Battleship", "Yamato", "``", "on", "their", "August", "1", ",", "1985", "issue", "as", "being", "the", "second", "most-successful", "upright", "arcade", "unit", "of", "the", "year", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "following", "table", "shows", "some", "of", "the", "various", "Middle", "English", "pronouns", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "rule", "Paul", "VI", "established", "in", "``", "Ingravescentem", "aetatem", "``", "(", "1970", ")", "and", "reiterated", "in", "``", "Romano", "Pontifici", "Eligendo", "``", "(", "1975", ")", "limited", "participation", "in", "the", "conclave", "to", "cardinals", "who", "had", "yet", "to", "reach", "the", "age", "of", "80", "on", "the", "first", "day", "of", "the", "conclave", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Sampi", "was", "also", "selected", "in", "the", "Eagles", "'", "2005", "losing", "Grand", "Final", "team", ",", "but", "took", "a", "major", "step", "backward", "in", "the", "2006", "season", ",", "losing", "his", "regular", "spot", "in", "the", "team", ",", "and", "only", "managing", "twelve", "games", "though", "poor", "form", ",", "and", "not", "playing", "in", "the", "Eagle", "'s", "victorious", "2006", "AFL", "Grand", "Final", "team", "."], "label": ["B-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Symptoms", "of", "floppy", "infant", "syndrome", "and", "the", "neonatal", "benzodiazepine", "withdrawal", "syndrome", "have", "been", "reported", "to", "persist", "from", "hours", "to", "months", "after", "birth", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "'s", "probable", "that", "the", "French", "revolution", "induced", "structural", "damage", "because", "a", "budget", "was", "allocated", "by", "the", "local", "administration", "for", "the", "repair", "of", "window", "panes", "and", "the", "roof", "in", "1797", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "CPP", "is", "headed", "by", "François", "Lucas", "Sainvil", "of", "Lespwa", "and", "has", "been", "characterized", "as", "leftist", ",", "populistic", "and", "anti-neoliberal", "in", "the", "press", "."], "label": ["O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "a", "2007", "interview", ",", "Cooke", "admitted", "to—while", "appreciating", "them—not", "paying", "much", "attention", "to", "awards", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "National", "Bank", "issued", "500", "korun", "notes", "from", "1946", ",", "whilst", "the", "government", "continued", "to", "issue", "notes", "between", "5", "and", "100", "korun", ",", "the", "1", "koruna", "note", "being", "replaced", "by", "a", "coin", "in", "1946", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "mid-2009", ",", "she", "started", "dating", "her", "``", "The", "Twilight", "Saga", "``", "co-star", "Robert", "Pattinson", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O"]}
{"text": ["Legal", "action", "began", "to", "become", "more", "prevalent", "in", "the", "1970s", "with", "the", "enactment", "of", "the", "Child", "Abuse", "Prevention", "and", "Treatment", "Act", "in", "1974", "in", "conjunction", "with", "the", "creation", "of", "the", "National", "Center", "for", "Child", "Abuse", "and", "Neglect", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Raiders", "finished", "the", "season", "7–9", ",", "improving", "on", "the", "prior", "season", "4–12", "record", ",", "but", "failing", "to", "make", "the", "playoffs", "for", "the", "third", "straight", "year", "and", "the", "16th", "time", "in", "the", "last", "17", "years", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Governor", "van", "Hoogenheim", "asked", "the", "States", "General", "for", "military", "assistance", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "April", "2017", ",", "it", "was", "announced", "that", "Olivier", "Assayas", "would", "write", "and", "direct", "``", "Wasp", "Network", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "supported", "the", "Patriot", "cause", "in", "the", "American", "Revolution", ",", "participating", "in", "the", "Wyoming", "Valley", "Massacre", "on", "the", "Patriot", "side", ",", "as", "well", "as", "the", "Battle", "of", "Newtown", "in", "1779", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", ",", "information", "about", "the", "Soviet", "famine", "of", "1932–1933", "was", "suppressed", "by", "the", "Soviet", "authorities", "until", "perestroika", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "also", "performed", "it", "on", "``", "Jimmy", "Kimmel", "Live", "!", "``"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "yard", "currently", "offers", "refurbishment", "and", "parts", "support", "for", "Contessa", "yachts", ",", "as", "well", "as", "refitting", "of", "other", "yacht", "makes", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "won", "fame", "there", "with", "her", "interpretation", "of", "Beethoven", "'s", "``", "Emperor", "''", "Concerto", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dingo", "also", "hosted", "the", "first", "series", "of", "``", "No", "Leave", ",", "No", "Life", "``", ",", "on", "Channel", "Seven", "."], "label": ["B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Kingston-Port", "Ewen", "Suspension", "Bridge", "at", "the", "foot", "of", "Wurts", "Street", "was", "completed", "in", "1921", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "part", "of", "this", "small", "fleet", ",", "the", "``", "Santos-Dumont", "``", "continued", "in", "this", "role", "until", "June", "1937", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "holds", "local", "history", "records", "along", "with", "the", "State", "Library", "of", "NSW", "and", "other", "state", "and", "local", "libraries", "and", "archives", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "also", "received", "the", "Schock", "Prize", "in", "1997", "and", "the", "Wolf", "Prize", "in", "2003", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Founded", "in", "1964", ",", "the", "University", "of", "Strathclyde", "Students", "'", "Association", "was", "formed", "when", "the", "Students", "'", "Associations", "of", "the", "Royal", "College", "of", "Science", "and", "Technology", "and", "of", "the", "Scottish", "College", "of", "Commerce", "amalgamated", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["They", "were", "forced", "to", "carry", "the", "pregnant", "woman", "back", "up", "the", "mountain", "after", "they", "could", "not", "afford", "the", "8000", "New", "Taiwan", "dollar", "deposit", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Paintings", "such", "as", "the", "``", "Mona", "Lisa", "``", "and", "various", "sculptures", "such", "as", "the", "Venus", "de", "Milo", "contain", "several", "golden", "rectangles", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "I-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "group", ",", "along", "with", "the", "NGC", "7582", "group", "form", "the", "Grus", "cloud", ",", "a", "region", "of", "elevated", "galaxy", "density", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "its", "name", "indicates", ",", "it", "serves", "the", "nearby", "Seoul", "Sports", "Complex", "including", "Seoul", "Olympic", "Stadium", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O"]}
{"text": ["Its", "semi-major", "axis", "(", "currently", "1.00096", "AU", ")", "is", "similar", "to", "that", "of", "Earth", "(", "1.00074", "AU", ")", ",", "but", "it", "has", "a", "relatively", "low", "eccentricity", "(", "0.18431", ")", "and", "moderate", "orbital", "inclination", "(", "7.640°", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["After", "the", "1917", "revolution", "and", "the", "Russian", "Civil", "War", ",", "the", "most", "of", "his", "poems", "was", "dedicated", "for", "the", "struggle", "against", "the", "Tsarism", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Web", "apps", "and", "pieces", "of", "content", "developed", "through", "Conduit", "'s", "platform", "can", "be", "distributed", "and", "exchanged", "online", "via", "the", "Conduit", "App", "Marketplace", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "I-product-software/game", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1978", ",", "she", "was", "awarded", "the", "Women", "in", "Film", "Crystal", "Award", "for", "outstanding", "women", "who", ",", "through", "their", "endurance", "and", "the", "excellence", "of", "their", "work", ",", "have", "helped", "to", "expand", "the", "role", "of", "women", "within", "the", "entertainment", "industry", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "Gilgamesh", "spurns", "her", "advances", ",", "Ishtar", "angrily", "goes", "to", "heaven", "and", "tells", "Anu", "that", "Gilgamesh", "has", "insulted", "her", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "building", "can", "be", "reached", "from", "Exit", "K", "of", "Central", "MTR", "Station", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "expanded", "during", "World", "War", "II", "into", "three", "Guards", "Divisions", ":"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Berne", "Convention", "for", "the", "Protection", "of", "Literary", "and", "Artistic", "Works", "(", "also", "referred", "to", "as", "just", "the", "Berne", "Convention", ")", "requires", "protection", "for", "all", "creative", "works", "in", "a", "fixed", "medium", "be", "automatic", ",", "and", "last", "for", "at", "least", "50", "years", "after", "the", "author", "'s", "death", "for", "any", "work", "except", "for", "photographic", "and", "cinematographic", "works", "."], "label": ["B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "tradition", "of", "more", "than", "30", "years", "began", "with", "the", "first", "broadcast", "on", "the", "NBC", "Pacific", "Network", ",", "on", "October", "24", ",", "1926", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Models", "of", "Fomalhaut", "b", "sculpting", "the", "star", "'s", "debris", "disk", "give", "a", "mass", "0.5", "times", "that", "of", "Jupiter", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "name", "was", "recorded", "in", "about", "1150", "as", "``", "Sahebroch", "''", "and", "in", "1386", "as", "``", "Saubro", "''", ";", "it", "possibly", "derives", "from", "Old", "Danish", "*", "''", "saghi", "''", ",", "``", "somewhat", "cut", "''", ",", "referring", "to", "tree-felling", ",", "and", "``", "brōk", "''", ",", "``", "swamp", "''", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", ",", "has", "been", "called", "one", "of", "the", "most", "malleable", "in", "English", "drama", ",", "lending", "itself", "to", "interpretations", "ranging", "from", "incredulous", "or", "scandalised", "to", "baffled", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["degree", "from", "New", "York", "University", "School", "of", "Law", ",", "a", "J.D", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Out", "of", "the", "40", "National", "Film", "Awards", "for", "Best", "Director", "given", "away", "till", "2007", ",", "Malayalam", "directors", "have", "received", "12", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", "were", "12", "recorded", "incidents/accidents", "involving", "Air", "Inter", "aircraft", "throughout", "37", "years", "of", "uninterrupted", "commercial", "operations", ",", "three", "of", "which", "were", "fatal", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "food", "court", "is", "between", "gates", "B6", "and", "B11", ";", "it", "has", "Carlos", "and", "Mickey", "'s", "Mexican", "Express", ",", "Pizza", "Hut", "Express", ",", "Quizno", "'s", "and", "Starbucks", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "O"]}
{"text": ["By", "1954", ",", "with", "Morton", "Grove", "growing", "rapidly", "in", "the", "post-World", "War", "II", "housing", "boom", ",", "the", "collection", "had", "grown", "to", "5,300", "volumes", "with", "an", "annual", "circulation", "of", "21,000", "items", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "battleships", "survived", "the", "Ice", "Cruise", "of", "1918", ",", "and", "``", "Andrei", "Pervozvanny", "``", "later", "ruthlessly", "gunned", "down", "the", "Krasnaya", "Gorka", "fort", "mutiny", "of", "1919", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "founded", "in", "1989", "and", "is", "affiliated", "to", "the", "Movement", "for", "Reform", "Judaism", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Vietnamese", "language", "has", "several", "mutually", "intelligible", "regional", "varieties", "(", "or", "dialects", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "is", "a", "BY", "Draconis", "variable", "that", "varies", "in", "brightness", "by", "about", "0.10", "magnitude", "over", "a", "period", "of", "15.8", "days", ",", "which", "is", "interpreted", "as", "the", "rotation", "period", "of", "the", "star", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "village", "'s", "name", "comes", "from", "the", "Māori-language", "word", "``", "Waipātiki", "''", ",", "meaning", "“", "water", "of", "the", "flounder", "”", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "returned", "to", "KNBC", "as", "an", "editorial", "assistant", "and", "eventually", "joined", "the", "special", "news", "projects", "department", "for", "the", "production", "of", "Channel", "4", "News", "'", "``", "O.J", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "sold", "at", "auction", "in", "2009", "for", "US", "$", "324,500", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["However", "disaster", "strikes", ",", "and", "the", "Great", "Kantō", "earthquake", "and", "subsequent", "fire", "destroy", "their", "factory", "and", "house", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "``", "New", "York", "Post", "``", "wrote", "that", "``", "some", "took", "his", "tweet", "as", "a", "call", "for", "violent", "insurrection", ".", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "I-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "annual", "Kidquake", "events", "bring", "over", "800", "K-5", "students", "from", "34", "classes", "to", "the", "San", "Francisco", "Public", "Library", "for", "two", "days", "of", "assemblies", "and", "intimate", "workshops", "with", "acclaimed", "children", "’", "s", "authors", ",", "and", "hundreds", "of", "free", "books", "and", "giveaways", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Gnumeric", "has", "an", "interface", "for", "the", "creation", "and", "editing", "of", "graphs", "different", "from", "other", "spreadsheet", "software", "."], "label": ["B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": [":", "Rebirth", "of", "the", "Cool", "``", ",", "was", "released", "between", "January", "and", "September", "2001", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", "are", "manuscript", "collections", "of", "kozachok", "melodies", "from", "the", "second", "half", "of", "the", "18th", "century", ",", "and", "printed", "collections", "begin", "to", "appear", "toward", "the", "end", "of", "that", "century", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Their", "design", "recalled", "the", "pro-democracy", "Wild", "Lily", "student", "movement", "of", "1990", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1988", ",", "it", "opened", "its", "50th", "Café", "de", "Coral", "restaurant", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O"]}
