{"text": ["During", "the", "trials", ",", "Auburn", "junior", "Charles", "Barkley", "impressed", "with", "his", "performance", "-", "most", "observers", "felt", "he", "and", "North", "Carolina", "shooting", "guard", "Michael", "Jordan", "were", "the", "two", "top", "performers", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "notes", "are", "then", "put", "into", "circulation", "by", "the", "Federal", "Reserve", "Banks", ",", "at", "which", "point", "they", "become", "liabilities", "of", "the", "Federal", "Reserve", "Banks", "and", "obligations", "of", "the", "United", "States", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "I-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "abrupt", "terminus", "at", "Chesapeake", "was", "envisioned", "to", "connect", "to", "Proctorville", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-GPE", "O"]}
{"text": ["is", "a", "1997", "role-playing", "video", "game", "developed", "by", "Sting", "Entertainment", "and", "published", "by", "ASCII", "Corporation", "for", "the", "Super", "Famicom", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "I-organization-showorganization/company", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Central", "European", "Diabetes", "Association", "(", "CEDA", ")", "is", "an", "international", "medical", "and", "scientific", "association", "."], "label": ["O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["While", "the", "function", "of", "TMEM128", "is", "poorly", "understood", ",", "it", "interacts", "with", "several", "proteins", "associated", "with", "the", "cell", "cycle", ",", "signal", "transduction", ",", "and", "memory", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["2", "Group", "RAF", ",", "RAF", "Second", "Tactical", "Air", "Force", "and", "located", "at", "RAF", "Oldenburg", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["His", "corporatist", "theories", "were", "strongly", "influenced", "by", "the", "statism", "of", "Georg", "Wilhelm", "Friedrich", "Hegel", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "total", "membership", "for", "all", "Eastern", "Catholic", "churches", "is", "at", "least", "16,336,000", "people", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Ury", "Estate", "is", "bounded", "on", "the", "west", "by", "Fetteresso", "Forest", "."], "label": ["B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Dilute", "nitric", "acid", "behaves", "as", "a", "typical", "acid", "in", "its", "reaction", "with", "most", "metals", "."], "label": ["B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "I-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Film", "directed", "and", "written", "by", "Gene", "Quintano", "and", "starring", "Emilio", "Estevez", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "N4", "is", "the", "flagship", "of", "the", "Washburn", "N-prefix", "guitar", "models", "."], "label": ["O", "B-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "previously", "an", "all-freight", "operator", "and", "intended", "to", "operate", "charter", "services", "from", "Amsterdam", "Schiphol", "Airport", "to", "Mediterranean", "holiday", "destinations", "starting", "later", "in", "2005", "using", "BAe", "ATP", "aircraft", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["At", "the", "end", "of", "August", "2006", ",", "Striker", "left", "the", "Raw", "brand", "to", "join", "ECW", ",", "making", "his", "debut", "on", "August", "23", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "period", "of", "historicism", ",", "learning", "from", "this", "national", "history", "became", "a", "general", "preoccupation", ",", "and", "dozens", "of", "works", "of", "popular", "history", "–", "notably", "by", "the", "educator", "Heinrich", "Zschokke", "and", "by", "the", "liberal", "historian", "André", "Daguet", "–", "were", "published", "to", "meet", "this", "demand", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "is", "a", "member", "of", "the", "Parker", "Institute", "for", "Cancer", "Immunotherapy", "and", "was", "selected", "as", "one", "of", "the", "inaugural", "Chan", "Zuckerberg", "Biohub", "investigators", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "I-organization-religion/other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Larry", "Pignagnoli", "already", "had", "success", "with", "Spagna", "in", "the", "late", "1980s", "and", "early", "1990s", "before", "he", "produced", "``", "Saturday", "Night", "``", "with", "Whigfield", "."], "label": ["B-person-soldier/other", "I-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O", "B-person-soldier/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["There", "is", "also", "Busyinternet", "and", "Surfline", "which", "offers", "wireless", "internet", "services", "through", "their", "omternet", "enabled", "devices", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "B-organization-showorganization/company", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "the", "second", "quarter", ",", "the", "Falcons", "regained", "the", "lead", "with", "kicker", "Morten", "Andersen", "getting", "a", "32-yard", "field", "goal", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-athlete", "I-person-athlete", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Wetherby", "Whaler", "is", "a", "chain", "of", "fish", "and", "chips", "restaurants", "in", "the", "United", "Kingdom", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Raveena", "Tandon", "also", "returned", "to", "Telugu", "cinema", "after", "a", "long", "hiatus", "with", "this", "film", "."], "label": ["B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "best", "known", "as", "leader", "of", "the", "moderate", "Irish", "Parliamentary", "Party", "(", "IPP", ")", "from", "1900", "until", "his", "death", "in", "1918", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["4th", "generation", "Apple", "TV", "s", "and", "newer", "can", "also", "stream", "content", "locally", "using", "third", "party", "apps", "such", "as", "Plex", "and", "VLC", "media", "player", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "2004–05", "Premier", "League", "season", "saw", "them", "finish", "15th", "out", "of", "16", "teams", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "I-organization-sportsteam/sportsleague", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Most", "of", "these", "hypoglycemic", "newborns", "are", "asymptomatic", "and", "have", "a", "normal", "blood", "glucose", "level", "within", "days", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-chemicalthing/medical/biologything/disease", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "had", "been", "given", "that", "seat", "by", "Sir", "John", "Honywood", ",", "but", "the", "two", "men", "fell", "out", "and", "Skipwith", "was", "not", "re-elected", "in", "1784", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "1950", "British", "Grand", "Prix", "was", "the", "first", "Formula", "One", "World", "Championship", "race", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "earned", "a", "Drama", "Desk", ",", "an", "Astaire", ",", "and", "an", "Outer", "Critics", "Circle", "Award", "nomination", "for", "his", "choreography", "in", "Cagney", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "O"]}
{"text": ["Educated", "at", "Westminster", "School", ",", "Cambridge", ",", "University", "of", "Oxford", ",", "Edinburgh", ",", "and", "Charing", "Cross", "Hospital", "Medical", "School", ",", "he", "completed", "medical", "training", "at", "the", "age", "of", "30", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "B-organization-education", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "B-organization-education", "O", "O", "B-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "I-organization-education", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "group", "was", "led", "by", "Hassan", "Sabarini", "(", "Abohelmi", ")", ",", "a", "Palestinian", "National", "Council", "member", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "I-person-politician", "O", "O", "B-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "I-organization-politicalparty/government/governmentagency", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "the", "ceremony", ",", "IIFA", "Awards", "were", "awarded", "in", "29", "competitive", "categories", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "regiment", "would", "later", "be", "stationed", "near", "Hampton", "Roads", "during", "the", "Peninsula", "Campaign", ",", "but", "experienced", "little", "fighting", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "I-location-road/railway/highway/transit/other", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Others", ",", "however", ",", "admitted", "to", "philosophical", "differences", "between", "Yavlinsky", "'s", "unspoken", "social", "democratic", "bent", "and", "the", "neoliberal", "orientation", "of", "his", "democratic", "opponents", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-person-politician", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Doug", "Carrion", "had", "replaced", "Lombardo", "by", "1986", "'s", "``", "Enjoy", "!"], "label": ["B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "first", "competition", "was", "on", "WWE", ".com", "on", "September", "10", ",", "which", "was", "also", "when", "the", "voting", "started", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "medium", "of", "instruction", "was", "Afrikaans", ",", "until", "the", "Soweto", "uprising", "in", "1976", ",", "when", "it", "changed", "to", "English", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "distance", "to", "this", "star", "can", "be", "determined", "through", "the", "parallax", "technique", ",", "yielding", "an", "estimate", "of", "roughly", "from", "Earth", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "airside", "part", "of", "the", "base", "was", "signed", "over", "to", "the", "existing", "commercial", "operator", "to", "form", "Kent", "International", "Airport", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "movie", "was", "approved", "by", "HBO", ",", "with", "Dinklage", "co-starring", "alongside", "Jamie", "Dornan", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "O", "O", "B-person-actor/director", "I-person-actor/director", "O"]}
{"text": ["In", "1952", "the", "two", "papers", "worked", "out", "a", "30-year", "agreement", ",", "known", "as", "the", "Joint", "Operating", "Agreement", "(", "JOA", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "B-other-law", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Eighteen", "new", "monsters", "were", "developed", "for", "the", "game", ",", "and", "while", "there", "were", "only", "3", "of", "the", "same", "boss", "monsters", "from", "the", "previous", "games", "(", "Rathalos", ",", "Rathian", "and", "Diablos", ")", ",", "their", "interactive", "AI", "was", "completely", "redesigned", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["And", "the", "same", "may", "be", "said", "of", "what", "is", "left", "of", "the", "undoubtedly", "Frankish", "book", "known", "as", "the", "``", "Missale", "Francorum", "``", "of", "the", "same", "date", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["When", "mounted", "inside", "a", "tank", ",", "the", "MG", "34", "also", "lacked", "a", "butt-stock", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-weapon", "I-product-weapon", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Upon", "the", "announcement", "of", "Nickelodeon", "signing", "the", "new", "show", "``", "The", "Mighty", "B", "!", "''"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "thus", "succeeded", "Paul", "Broca", "who", "served", "in", "this", "position", "until", "1880", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-person-artist/author/scholar", "I-person-artist/author/scholar", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Motivation", "to", "create", "CiMPLE", "was", "to", "help", "do", "away", "for", "rote", "memorization", "of", "language", "syntax", "while", "programming", "a", "robotic", "kit", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["On", "the", "25th", "of", "November", "2018", ",", "the", "Sullom", "Voe", "Terminal", "reached", "a", "milestone", "40th", "anniversary", "since", "first", "oil", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Since", "ancient", "times", ",", "it", "has", "been", "especially", "revered", ",", "ranking", "with", "the", "Grand", "Shrine", "of", "Ise", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "I-building-airport/other", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "faults", "and", "joints", "are", "associated", "with", "the", "uplift", "of", "the", "Black", "Hills", "approximately", "58", "to", "54", "million", "years", "ago", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "part", "of", "the", "``", "All-New", ",", "All-Different", "Marvel", "''", "event", ",", "White", "Tiger", "appears", "as", "a", "member", "of", "Sunspot", "'s", "incarnation", "of", "the", "``", "New", "Avengers", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O"]}
{"text": ["for", "deposits", "from", "source", "vents", ",", "making", "them", "younger", "than", "Mazama", "Ash", "deposits", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Since", "the", "late", "20th", "century", ",", "the", "Argentine", "peso", "has", "experienced", "a", "substantial", "rate", "of", "devaluation", ",", "reaching", "25", "%", "year-on-year", "inflation", "rate", "in", "2017", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "manuscript", "is", "currently", "housed", "at", "the", "Sackler", "Library", "(", "Papyrology", "Rooms", ",", "P.", "Oxy", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "1999", "Nissan", "Maxima", "also", "saw", "some", "minor", "changes", ":", "an", "Anti-Theft", "Engine", "Immobilizer", "was", "standard", "using", "a", "chip", "in", "the", "ignition", "key", ",", "as", "well", "as", "some", "minor", "body", "trims", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-food/other", "I-product-food/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "``", "lhakang", "``", "contains", "a", "number", "of", "fine", "murals", "—", "the", "central", "image", "being", "that", "of", "Guru", "Rinpoche", "(", "Padmasambhava", ")", ",", "with", "images", "of", "the", "five", "Nyingma", "Yidam-Protectors", "and", "Tseumar", "and", "Tamdrin", "in", "glass", "cases", "around", "the", "walls", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "B-building-airport/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-god", "I-other-god", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "B-other-god", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "was", "inspired", "by", "the", "1966", "science", "fiction", "film", "``", "Fantastic", "Voyage", "``", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "I-art-music/film/broadcastprogram", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["He", "was", "one", "of", "the", "few", "people", "to", "have", "played", "a", "role", "in", "the", "rebellion", "of", "1867", ",", "the", "1916", "Rising", "and", "the", "Irish", "War", "of", "Independence", "(", "1919–1921", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["For", "other", "countries", "see", "List", "of", "World", "War", "II", "aces", "by", "country"], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "I-event-attack/battle/war/militaryconflict", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Insular", "Mountains", "extend", "from", "Vancouver", "Island", "in", "the", "south", "to", "the", "Queen", "Charlotte", "Islands", "in", "the", "north", "on", "the", "British", "Columbia", "Coast", "."], "label": ["B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "I-location-island/mountain", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "I-location-bodiesofwater/park", "O"]}
{"text": ["Meanwhile", ",", "the", "studio", "received", "in", "tax", "credits", "through", "the", "UK", "government", "'s", "video", "games", "tax", "relief", "(", "VGTR", ")", "scheme", ",", "19", "%", "of", "the", "scheme", "'s", "entire", "payout", "since", "its", "establishment", "in", "2014", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "I-event-disaster/other", "O", "B-event-disaster/other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "second", "series", "aired", "on", "Saturdays", "at", "9:25am", "on", "CITV", "on", "ITV1", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O", "B-organization-media/newspaper", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "basic", "syllable", "form", "of", "Gbe", "languages", "is", "commonly", "rendered", "(", "C1", ")", "(", "C2", ")", "V", "(", "C3", ")", ",", "meaning", "that", "there", "at", "least", "has", "to", "be", "a", "nucleus", "V", ",", "and", "that", "there", "are", "various", "possible", "configurations", "of", "consonants", "(", "C1-3", ")", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Around", "the", "same", "time", ",", "the", "locomotive", "cabs", "were", "modernised", "with", "new", ",", "rationalised", "control", "layouts", "and", "additional", "noise", "insulation", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "I-product-ship/car/airplane/train", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["``", "Chariots", "of", "Fire", "``", "opened", "in", "previews", "9", "May", "at", "London", "'s", "Hampstead", "Theatre", ",", "and", "officially", "opened", "there", "on", "22", "May", "."], "label": ["O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Parliament", "Act", "1911", "was", "amended", "by", "the", "Parliament", "Act", "1949", "(", "12", ",", "13", "&", "amp", ";", "14", "Geo", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Akutagawa", "Prize", "was", "given", "every", "six", "months", "to", "rising", "authors", "of", "original", "literature", "(", "Sōsaku", ")", "that", "were", "published", "in", "any", "newspaper", "or", "magazine", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-award", "I-other-award", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Australian", "dollar", ",", "however", ",", "was", "effectively", "pegged", "to", "the", "British", "pound", "at", "an", "equivalent", "value", "of", "approximately", "1", "gram", "of", "gold", "."], "label": ["O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["WMV", "HD", "mandates", "the", "use", "of", "WMV", "9", "for", "its", "certification", "program", ",", "at", "quality", "levels", "specified", "by", "Microsoft", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-product-software/game", "O"]}
{"text": ["During", "trading", "on", "September", "20", ",", "2007", ",", "it", "met", "the", "U.S.", "dollar", "at", "parity", "for", "the", "first", "time", "since", "November", "25", ",", "1976", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Signatories", "of", "the", "Convention", "on", "Cluster", "Munitions", "have", "accepted", "restrictions", "on", "the", "use", "of", "cluster", "munitions", ",", "including", "artillery", "shells", ":", "the", "treaty", "requires", "that", "a", "weapon", "so", "defined", "must", "contain", "nine", "or", "fewer", "submunitions", ",", "which", "must", "each", "weigh", "more", "than", "4", "kilograms", ",", "be", "capable", "of", "detecting", "and", "engaging", "a", "single", "target", ",", "and", "contain", "electronic", "self-destruct", "and", "self-deactivation", "systems", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "B-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "I-other-law", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["It", "'s", "believed", "that", "there", "is", "some", "mention", "of", "the", "Khasa", "language", "in", "texts", "like", "Manusmriti", ",", "Rajatarangini", "and", "the", "Puranas", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-language", "I-other-language", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "O", "O", "B-art-writtenart/painting", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "implies", "that", "either", "Proxima", "Centauri", "b", "was", "formed", "elsewhere", "in", "a", "manner", "still", "to", "be", "determined", ",", "or", "the", "current", "disc", "models", "for", "stellar", "formation", "are", "in", "need", "of", "revision", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "I-other-astronomything", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["Closing", "ceremonies", "and", "outdoor", "events", "(", "mainly", "track", "and", "field", ")", "took", "place", "at", "Centennial", "Park", "Stadium", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O"]}
{"text": ["As", "of", "July", "2017", ",", "it", "had", "176", "Taco", "Cabana", "stores", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "new", "airport", "cost", "178", "million", "Norwegian", "krone", "and", "opened", "on", "9", "September", "1999", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-other-currency", "I-other-currency", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Women", "'s", "400", "metres", "individual", "medley", "heats", "were", "held", "at", "the", "Melbourne", "Sports", "and", "Aquatic", "Centre", "on", "the", "21", "March", "2006", "at", "10:38", "AEST", "."], "label": ["O", "B-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "I-event-sportsevent", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "I-building-theater/sportsfacility/library", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "Hotel", "Canberra", "was", "the", "first", "hostel", "to", "be", "built", "-", "in", "1925", "-", "to", "house", "politicians", "and", "even", "if", "a", "workman", "could", "afford", "the", "tariff", "he", "would", "not", "be", "allowed", "to", "stay", "there", "."], "label": ["O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["She", "is", "most", "often", "seen", "in", "the", "current", "New", "X-Men", "title", "while", "tending", "to", "the", "wounded", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["The", "spin-off", "brand", "did", "not", "appear", "to", "work", "as", "planned", ",", "and", "they", "are", "now", "just", "known", "as", "Brewers", "Fayre", "and", "have", "the", "same", "menu", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-building-hotel/restaurant", "I-building-hotel/restaurant", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["This", "company", "was", "linked", "to", "the", "Māori", "protest", "movement", "and", "they", "toured", "a", "theatre", "production", "in", "1979", "-", "1980", "to", "marae", "and", "schools", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "I-event-election/protest", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
{"text": ["A", "local", "record", ",", "``", "Avia", "Ripensis", "``", "(", ")", ",", "mentions", "the", "existence", "of", "a", "local", "church", "in", "1340", "."], "label": ["O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "B-art-other", "I-art-other", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O", "O"]}
